>> Let's start this demo by
taking a look at a
synchronous example,
and then we're going to spin this
into the asynchronous example,
So for our example in both cases,
what we're going to do is we're
going to make a call out to
a little web service that does
very simple things for us,
In this case, what it's going
to do is it's going to delay,
It's basically a REST API
version of a sleep call,
I personally don't like doing
demos that really
depend on sleep calls,
You are going to notice,
I'll do a little bit
of that in the other one,
But I generally try to avoid that,
It's because I don't think that
they're necessarily real-world,
that whenever I look at that,
I'm like, "Oh, well, you
want to improve performance?
Just take out the sleep
call, problem solved,"
Maybe that's just me, but yes,
So instead, I always like to
call out to some other service,
This is just a simple
way that we can do this,
So more than anything else,
it's a fancy sleep call,
just because of the fact that
we're calling an endpoint,
You're going to notice to start with,
that we are pulling in
the timeit library,
I'm a huge fan of the timeit library,
just because it gives us
the ability real quick
and easy to see how
long something takes,
So we're just going to
set up our default timer,
and we'll stop and start
a stopwatch effectively,
and then print out
however long this took,
We're going to bring in
the request library,
which we talked about in
our prior Python videos,
This is by far,
the most common library for
making HTTP/HTTPS calls,
The thing about the
request library though,
is the fact that it is synchronous,
meaning that it's always
going to stop execution,
If we want to do this asynchronously,
we are going to need to
do something different,
maybe use a different library,
That's actually what
I'm going to do in
my other demo is use
a different library,
a library that's built for
asynchronous programming,
Now, inside of here,
I'm just going to ignore the little
prints and things like that,
just because all that that's doing is
just making the demo
look a little prettier,
So we're just saying, "Hey,
we're starting this, stopping this,
starting this, stopping this,"
So I'm not going to
focus on the prints,
But instead, I want to
focus in on line 6 here,
which is where we're now
going to make our get
called and we're going
to go get the text here,
Now, you're going to
notice that we've got
one parameter that's called delay,
Delay is going to be x number of
seconds that we want to delay,
You'll notice that when
we run the demo here,
that in our demo,
we're going to go ahead and
make a two second delay call,
and then a three second delay call,
and then eventually print
out however long it took,
Now, all of that's wrapped up
inside of a neat little run demo,
It's wrapped up inside
of main for reasons
we'll talk about in the next section,
and now we're just
simply calling main,
So now, let's go ahead and bring this
together by saying python and
then my little sync_demo,py,
What you're going to
notice is that this
is performing the
operation synchronously,
So it started the two second
delay, and then finished,
It started the three second
You'll notice that the entire
operation took 6,3 seconds,
Again, that extra 1,3 is
just because of how long
it took to spin up and tear down
the appropriate connections,
That's not necessarily a
great way to program that,
If I'm working with something
that's single user,
maybe I'm putting this inside
of a Jupyter Notebook,
By the way, there might
be another course where
we talk about Jupyter
Notebooks, go check it out,
But if I'm putting this
inside of a Jupyter Notebook,
it's just me, I'm not
necessarily doing anything else,
I can't move without
waiting for the value here,
then just go ahead and do this,
But if I am building something
up that's going to be
multi-user or I want it
to be better performant,
then I'm going to
need a better answer,
So this is that next section
that I'm talking about,
This is now where
we're going to get in,
and start to work asynchronously,
So what I want to highlight
up at the very top here,
is we're pulling in two
little libraries here,
We're pulling in,
first of all, aiohttp,
Now, the big thing that I
want to highlight about
this is the fact that this
is another library here,
So it's not the request library,
this is not built in with Python,
but rather, it's a different library,
Aiohttp is all about asyncio
and making HTTP calls,
Now, the way that this does its magic
is it's all based around
a session object,
Typically, what you'll
do is you'll create
one session and keep reusing that
over and over and over again,
This actually gives you a little
bit of additional performance,
because of the fact that it's able to
reuse that connection if possible,
So it does a little bit of
connection pooling
for us automatically,
In fact, we can see right
here that we're going
to create that session one time,
Now, you are going to notice
that if we're going to
use await inside of a with,
that we do need to
mark that as async,
Now, why is an async important here?
Well, the reason that
async is important is
because it's basically
telling our runtime,
"Hey, there's going to be
an await command in here,"
The key to an await command working
is that my runtime needs to
understand what that is,
My runtime needs to understand,
"Hey, we need to pause here,
That's why we have that async,"
Now, having that on a method might
make sense, because after all,
we're going to call await
eventually on that method,
so maybe it makes sense there,
Then on top of that,
when the method ends,
it just simply ends at that point,
So we want to make
sure that the runtime
knows that somewhere in here,
there's potentially
going to be a blocker,
there's going to be an await,
With behaves in the exact same way,
That if you remember back
to the prior module,
we saw a with,
The whole thing about with,
is that it's going to do
automatic clean up for us,
Well, we don't want
it to clean things
up before we're done using them,
So again, when we're
going to have that await,
we're going to pause right here,
wait for something else to
complete somewhere else,
As a result, we need
to make sure that
the outside is aware of that fact,
That's what async is doing,
is it's letting
everything know, "Hey,
inside of here, we're going to
have a pause for something else,
don't leave without me,"
That's basically it here,
So that's why we have that both
on the with statement here,
and on the little function,
What you're also going
to notice right here
is we're going to do the exact
same thing with that load_data,
put it in a two and a
three second delay,
But this time, we're going
to pass in the session,
Then if we spin it on up to the top,
what I want you to notice
is a similar syntax here,
where now we're going to go
ahead and call that session get,
and then we're going to go ahead
and grab the text from that,
Now, you're going to notice
that I've got my
await right here because
calling out to get the text,
that's going to be an
asynchronous operation,
So that's what's going on here,
That's the setup for that aiohttp,
So it's a little bit
more work than we had
for our requests because of the
fact that it's asynchronous,
Now what makes the asynchronous magic
happen in Python is this asyncio,
Now, asyncio is new to Python 3,4,
and it's had a lot of
changes since then,
There's constant turn here,
So I do want to highlight the fact
that we're recording
this at a point in time,
So the code that's here will only
run on Python 3,7 or higher,
Just this example here,
So if you're running this on a
prior version, you can do this,
It's just a different
way to go about this,
I really like this implementation,
This feels much more natural,
especially as somebody who's worked
with async/await in
other environments,
So this only going to work
on Python 3,7 or higher,
So you're going to notice that
we pull in this asyncio library,
Now, what you're going to notice with
asyncio is we're now going
to create these tasks,
This is basically that process
or that promise rather,
This is where I'm going to say, "Hey,
load_data, go do
something, go do this,
Then when you're done, make sure,
promise me that you'll let
me know that you're done,
Promise me that you'll
go get that value,
and you'll give it back
to me when I ask for it,"
That's what's happening here,
So we're setting that up,
Then what we're going to do is
we're going to say, "All right,
Now, we're ready for that value,"
So now I'm going to say, "Hey,
give me the value back
from the two_task,
Hey now, give me that value
back from the three_task,"
Now, I'm not printing
them out in this case,
mostly just because
it generates a lot of
noise on the screen because
what the text gives me
back is the full JSON
response from the endpoint,
It just gives me a lot
of extraneous data,
So I'm just trying to keep things
relatively streamlined here,
so I'm not going to worry
about printing that out,
I'm just simulating
grabbing the values here,
That's really the important part is
that ability to go ahead
and grab the value,
Now, what's great about setting up
those tasks is the fact that
I can do other work here,
So that other work might
take a little bit of time,
so this is now where I'm
going to do that sleep,
So now, I'm going to sleep
for a second and then I'm
going to print out doing other work,
Then finally, at the very end,
we'll print out
whatever the timer was,
When I run this code,
what you're going to notice,
let me just clear my screen here,
is it starts both timers,
it does the other work,
it finishes both timers,
Then the total elapsed time
that it took was 3,3 seconds,
Again, that 0,3 is the build up
and tear down of the HTTP calls,
But now, what I want you to
notice is the fact that we
actually had three
"long-running operations,"
We have the one second sleep
timer, and then the two,
and the three second
delay that we were
calling out to that HTTP service,
and in the end,
it only took 3,3 seconds,
This is what async/await
is all about,
It gives us this ability,
It gives us the ability too without
necessarily having to spin out
different threads and
manage them and so forth,
be able to still take advantage of
a little bit of
potentially multicore,
or just the ability for Python
now to be able to swap
things on and off
because now we've given
it a little bit of
a heads up of the fact that
certain operations are
going to be long-running,
and it's okay if it
does something else,
That is async/await inside of Python,
Now, I again want to
stress the fact that
there's a lot that's going
on here with async/ await,
and we are going to link to
more information inside
of the GitHub page,
So if you want to keep
digging into async/await,
you can absolutely do this,
I will say that in
today's day and age,
understanding async/await is one of
those core concepts that you will
want to become familiar with,
I also want to highlight this fact,
Asyncio in Python is still
actively being developed,
things are going to change over time,
So the code that's here,
while it will likely continue to
work in Python 3,7 and higher,
there's a very good chance
how things work may change,
and there's also a very good
chance that there might be cool
new fancy ways to do things
as well in the future,
So again, we're recording
this at a point in time,
Right now, this is the
way that things behave,
things could always
change in the future,
So all of that is how we can
do async/await in Python,