>> Let's see our little
framework in action here,
So what I've got is
my two little classes here
of loggable and connection,
Again, what loggable is going
to do for me is enable logging,
my connection is going to allow
me then to handle my connection,
Setting up the couple of
properties for title and server,
and then setting up the couple
little functions that are
going to simulate whatever it is
that we're trying to do here,
So in my case, it's going
to be writing out to
the log file and connecting
out to the database,
Then what you're going to
notice is that I've got
my little SQL database
that I'm creating here,
My little SQL database
is then going to
inherit from both
connection and loggable,
We're going to set up the
title and the server,
Then what you're going
to notice right here is,
here's our little fancy framework,
Our fancy framework is
going to check to see,
hey, did we inherit from connection?
If we did, we'll run
the connect code,
Hey, did we inherit from Loggable?
If we did, then we'll go
ahead and run the log code,
Actually I'm going to
move this down real quick
here just because I'm going to want
to play around with a
couple of things here,
so I'm just going to move that down,
No big thing going on there,
so just move that down,
So there's my little framework,
Now, I'm going to go ahead
and use the framework,
So I'm going to inherit from
connection and the Loggable
to enable that behavior,
So now, when I create
the instance and I go
ahead and pass it through
my high-end framework,
What I'm going to notice is that
it's going to tell me that it's
logging the SQL connection demo
and that it's connecting
to some server,
There we go, Sure enough,
that's exactly what we get,
So it's connecting out to the
database, log the message,
Because again, that is what we
went ahead and inherited from,
Now, what's great about this
little framework that I've created
here is the fact that if I
want to do something else,
so let's say that I'm going
to create a brand new class,
and this is going to
be just a logger,
Then what I can do is just
inherit from Loggable,
I can go ahead and set up
my init just like that,
and we don't care about the super,
Then I'm going to say self,title,
You'll notice that I get IntelliSense
here because I'm
inheriting from Loggable,
Except that to be just logging,
go ahead and save that,
Let's go ahead and create
a brand new instance,
So we'll say, just_log
equal to JustLog,
Then we'll go ahead and
just log like that,
Pass that in again to our
very fancy framework,
Now, what we're going to
notice is the fact that
it's only going to do our logging,
So now with this framework,
what I've enabled for
developers that are
going to be using
this is that ability,
So if you want to be able to
connect, you can do that,
If you want to be able to log,
you can do that,
So really a nice way to set up
and work with that framework,
So like I mentioned at the outset,
we want to typically avoid setting
up multiple inheritance when
we're writing our own code,
unless we happen to be
setting up a framework,
but instead we will be
using it quite frequently,
So when we're using other frameworks,
So if you're heading out and
maybe learning Django or
learning another framework
that depends upon Mixin's,
this is the magic that's happening,
That you inherit from
yet another class,
you go ahead and set up
a couple of properties,
maybe set up a couple of methods,
and then voila something really
cool is now happening
inside of your application,
This is what's making it happen,
It's doing exactly what I did here,
It's checking to see, did
you inherit from a class?
If you did, then we'll go ahead
and call a couple of things on that,
So that is multiple inheritance
and Mixins in Python,