>> When you start working with code,
at some point you're going to have to
start interacting
with the file system,
You're going to either need
to read files or write to
files and figuring out
what directory you're in
and issues like that,
So let's take a look at some
of the Python commands and
libraries we can use to work
with the file system itself,
Now, in the earlier days of Python,
we typically used os,path,
and that's operating system path,
So we would literally call
the operating system and say,
what path are we in?
Now, the great thing
is, in Python 3,6,
they actually added a new library,
pathlib, which includes
a class called path,
That's a cleaner way and actually
slightly faster way to access
information about things
like what directory I'm in?
What files are in that
directory and so on,
because it doesn't require
accessing and calling the
operating system itself,
So python 3,6 or higher,
you definitely want to be
using path and path lead,
But if you're looking at
older code from someone else,
just be aware you might see
something called os,path,
But we're going to
focus on going forward,
what we want to be doing
as we move forward,
So it's the path libraries,
So we're going to import that
library to be able to use it,
and once we've done that,
then we can simply use cwd for
current working directory,
So if you want to retrieve
what directory I'm in right
now, it's just path,cwd,
The other thing you
commonly want to do
is we want to know a full path name,
So the name of the directory
and that is slash or backslash,
and the file name,
So we want to include that in
the full name so you can
actually build that,
There's this wonderful function
called join path which will
actually build you
the correct structure
of a directory name and
the file name together,
Another common test we do,
because often before we write
to a file or read a file,
we want to check if the file already
exists because we might write
good code where we're checking
to see if file exists
before we try and read it,
So we don't just get error
messages causing things to crash,
It's much more elegant to say,
hey, let's check if the file exists,
If it doesn't, maybe we
return our own error message,
So controlled error handling
instead of having a function fail,
So another great feature is
to be able to check and see
if a file exists using
the Boolean variable,
So few features we have,
and if you do that, what
you'll see come back is
you would see there's your
current working directory there,
You can see the full path name
with the directory name
and the file name,
You can see in this case,
I haven't actually created
a file called new file,
So when I asked if that file
exists even though I've
created a file path for it,
the file itself is not there,
so it returns a false,
Now, in directories, the other
common thing we end up doing,
this comes up when we're maybe doing
data science and
reading a set of files,
or we're just moving data
from one place to another is
we might need to check things
like go into a directory,
get a list of the contents
of that directory,
get a list of the files, etc,
We can keep using the path
library for that as well,
We can request the parent directory,
We can ask, is this a
directory or a file?
By using, is directory
true-false is file true-false,
For child in parent,
it's a fantastic one for just getting
a list of the contents of
a particular directory,
So if I was to run that,
I might see something like if I
pass it the working directory,
Well, the working directory
is a directory name,
So is it a directory true?
Is it a file false?
What's contents of the
current working directory?
It might be something like
following a few code examples here,
Now, files is the other one
we're going to be working with,
We're going to talk about
reading and writing
to files in the next module,
So I'm just talking
about how do I find out
information about what
files I have first,
So don't worry, we're going
to get to reading and
writing to files in the next module,
But just to find out
information about your files,
Some of the things we can see
once you know that working directory,
you can do things like
retrieve the file name,
retrieve the file suffix,
retrieve the folder name,
or even information
like what size in it
or when was it last-modified?
So you might determine
if maybe there was
a program that was supposed to
modify the file in the background,
has that program completed before
I go reading it and so on,
So if you were to run this code,
you'd see something like, Oh,
the file is demo,text and
the extension is,txt,
It's in the folder file system and
its size is say, 11 kilobytes,
So those are some of the
neat things we can do,
Let's go try it out
in some actual code,