>> There's an old
coworker of mine who is,
I'm assuming still to this day,
really fond of saying,
we're not launching rockets here,
and that phrase has stuck
with me for my entire career,
The point that he was trying to
make when he would say that phrase,
"We're not launching rockets here,"
is that whatever it
is that we're doing,
it's really not necessarily
all that complex,
We're not necessarily
breaking new ground,
we're not launching rockets,
and as a result,
whatever it is that we're doing,
whatever problems it is
that we're trying to solve,
chances are somebody else
has already been there and
they've already built
some form of a solution,
One great example of
that is when you're
dealing with a CRUD web application,
CRUD of course, stemming for Create,
Retrieve, Update, and Delete,
This is really a line of business
application where I've got data,
I want to be able to manipulate it,
I want to be able to search
for different items,
I want to be able to filter and
like do all of those basic things,
I want to create records,
I want to get them back,
I want to be able to update them,
I want to be able to delete them,
Basically, every Web
Developer at some point
has created some form of
an application that's going
to be a CRUD application,
Again, create, retrieve,
update, delete,
So rather than every time
we need to create one of
those types of applications,
go off and start setting up
all of the code on our own,
Start setting up all of
the codes to do paging,
which is a real challenge,
Let's instead use code that
somebody else has already created,
and one framework that
has done exactly that,
and a framework that I'm a huge fan
of is this little
thing called Django,
Django is going to help
make its magic happen,
Help allow me to integrate
with it by using
this little thing called
multiple inheritance or mixins,
I bet you're wondering when I
was finally going to get to
the text that was
behind me, Here we are,
So what I'm really trying to do
here is I'm trying
to set the stage for
when and why it is that you
might decide to use
something like this,
and quite frequently it's
because we want to be
able to clip into a framework,
Well, let's define some
terms to start with,
Let's go ahead and talk a little
bit about multiple inheritance,
Multiple inheritance
as the name implies,
means that I'm able to inherit
from multiple classes,
Now, you're also going to notice that
some people will call this mixins
for reasons that we'll start
to see a little bit later,
Now, one thing to note about
multiple inheritance is that it's
actually a little controversial,
You're going to notice that a
lot of programming languages,
Java, C-Sharp, don't support
multiple inheritance,
Yes, they'll allow you to
implement multiple interfaces,
It's a different
conversation altogether,
but they only allow you to
inherit from one class,
and the reason that they've made
that decision is because
well, quite frankly,
multiple inheritance can
get messy really quick,
that a lot of Developers
don't necessarily use it real
well because it can get complicated,
So why have it then?
Where might we use this?
Well, it's useful in those
exact types of scenarios
where what I'm looking to
do is to either take
advantage of a framework,
Again, I mentioned
Django at the outset,
or I'm trying to streamline
repetitious operations
or repetitive operations
that I'm trying to do the same
thing over and over again,
you just see where that's
going with that joke,
All right, So let's highlight
then this scenario,
So here's what I want
to be able to create,
I want to create my own
framework where I'm
going to give you the ability
to connect to a database,
All that you need to do is give me
the name of the database
that you want to connect to,
In addition, I also want to
give you the ability to quickly
log out to the screen
or to a file system behind
the scenes or wherever it is,
But I don't want you to
worry about any of that,
I don't want you to have to worry
about how to write out to a file,
Or maybe we've decided
to update things that are we're going
to write out to the event log,
I don't want you to worry about that,
I want to give you the ability
instead to focus in on the code that
you're creating and not worry
about the nitty-gritty,
I don't want you to worry about
the exact machinations of
how we're going to connect
out to the database,
You just tell me where to connect,
we'll take care of the rest for you,
I don't want you to worry about
how we're going to do logging,
Just tell me what it is
that you want to log,
I'll take care of the rest for you,
and this is where
something like mixins
or multiple inheritance
can really shine,
Because now I can take
advantage of each one of
these depending on what
it is that I'm doing,
So maybe I've got some
operation over here where all
that I want to be able to do is
just write out to the logfile,
No database required,
Maybe I've got something
going on where I want
to be able to write
out to a database,
but no logging is required,
This is where mixins come into play,
So let's break all of this
down with our code here,
So you're going to notice that I'm
going to create two classes here,
One that's called Loggable
and the other one that's
called Connection,
With loggable, what I'm going to look
for is I'm going to look for,
in this case, a title,
and then I'm going to
go ahead and login,
So because of course,
I'm trying to keep things a
little bit straight forward,
I'm going to just go ahead and
print it out to the screen,
So I will print out whatever it
is that's inside of the title,
The other thing that I want
you to notice is that I'm
going to set up a connection here,
and again, just to try and simulate
how it is that we're connecting out,
I'm just going to print out, "Hey,
we're connecting out to
whatever the name of the server
is," and then right here,
I'm going to go ahead and
store the name of the server,
So there's our loggable and
there is our connection,
Now, the next question
then becomes, well,
if I'm going to keep
building this framework,
how am I going to put this to action?
Here's my really fancy framework,
So what my framework is
going to do is it's going
to take whatever item it
is that you give to it,
and then I'm going to look to say,
hey, did you inherit from connection?
That's what his instance
is going to tell me,
and if you did now I know
that I can call connect,
Then I'm going to go
ahead and check to see,
did you inherit from loggable?
That's what his instance
again is going to do for me,
and if you did, then I can
go ahead and call log,
It's such a wonderful toy,
little obscure reference for
my own entertainment there,
Now, I can go ahead and
create a class here,
So I'm going to create
a database class,
and my database class is
going to inherit from
Connection and it's going
to inherit from Loggable,
and now all I need to do to
enable the appropriate
functionality is go
ahead and set up those two
little properties right there,
and then if I wanted to do anything
else inside of this class,
I'm absolutely able to do that,
The key thing here is the fact
that if I want to enable logging,
I just simply inherit from
Loggable and then set up
whatever my title is,
If I want to enable
connecting to a database,
I simply inherit from
connection and then set up
whatever it is that I need to
set up, and then later on,
if I decide I'm going
to create something
else that's not going to be loggable,
well, then just don't
inherit from loggable,
That's really it, So now,
I create an instance of that class,
I call my super-duper
high-end framework,
and eventually what we would
notice is the printout on
the screen that it's going
to connect to the database and
it's going to log our message,
Now, I'm going to get to the
code in just a moment here,
but I want to close by saying this,
The vast majority of the time
that you're going to use
multiple inheritance
or mixins is a when you're
using an existing framework,
There's this great little
thing called the code smell,
where it's really trying
to indicate the fact that
something might not be right,
Something just smells wrong,
something smells unpleasant,
and multiple inheritance can
quite frequently be a code smell,
If you're setting up
your own environment,
your own little application,
and you've got multiple
inheritance going on,
I'm not going to say that
you're doing the wrong thing,
but what I am going to say is
that's frequently a code smell,
Chances are you're not pointed
in the right direction,
Now, if you are creating
a re-useable framework,
then absolutely this could be
one of the solutions that
you decide to choose from,
Again, you'll see this
in a lot of frameworks,
Django being my favorite,
I love Django, Django is
near and dear to my heart,
So you might be using this with
some additional frameworks,
You might be creating
your own framework where you're
going to simulate
something like that,
But typically for most
of the applications that
you're going to be using,
setting up a multiple
inheritance hierarchy,
probably not what you're
looking for, Code smell,
Using a framework that
uses multiple inheritance,
that's something that is very common,
All that being said,
let's go ahead and take
a look at our code demo,