>> So let's see how we can use
the with command to clean up
our code when we're
working with objects
that need to be closed
when we finish them,
Classic example is when you
are working with a file,
So what we would very commonly do in
our code is we would use
something like a try statement,
So we can say, hey, open up
our file and write to it,
Now, if everything goes
well and you've successfully
written to the file,
we want to make sure we close
that file stream when we're done,
we do not want to leave it
open, So really important,
But if we open to it and
write to it and somewhere along
the way something goes wrong,
we still need to make
sure we close it,
So that's why we put
this into a try finally,
So regardless of whether
we got an error or not,
it always closes the stream,
Super important code,
So we could run this code,
If we just run that here,
You'll see it does successfully
create this output,txt file,
and it'll write Lorem
ipsum out to that file,
But I can replace all of this
code using the with command,
So what the with command does
for me is it allows me to write
some really clean code
for any type of object where
there is that requirement,
always close it when you're done,
the width command will basically
automatically close it for you
when the commands are complete,
So in this case, I say,
well with in this case,
opening a file stream called
output,txt to write
to and do a write,
When it's finished, if
everything goes well,
it'll close it for me,
and if there's an error,
it'll still close it for me,
So this is really exactly the
same code as try finally,
but so much cleaner,
so much easier to read
once you get used to it,
So if we run this code,
we're going to see
exactly the same output,
There we go, and we'll see that
output,txt file written there,
But this time I did it
with the with command,
So this way I guarantee
that my file stream is
going to get closed when I'm
finished working with it,
regardless of whether or not I
had an error when the
code was running,
This is not just limited
to file streams,
any of these objects where there's
that requirement to close
it when you're done,
you can use a with command,
Make it your best friend,