>> Okay, So we've learned how
to work with the file system,
now we're learning how to actually
read and write actual files,
So let's suppose we
have a file like this,
which we want to be able to
read with our Python code,
So we have just three
simple lines of text in
a file called demo,txt
and we want to read that,
So what we're going
to do is we're going
to open up a file stream saying,
let's read demo,txt, and
we're opening it for reading,
We could have left this part RT off,
it will default to a
text file reading,
In case you're having problems,
sometimes when you try to read files,
you never quite sure
why isn't working,
maybe the file isn't there,
maybe it's not readable,
These really common programming
issues to run into,
So you might do things
like check and see
if it's readable before
you try to read it,
when you're trying to debug
why you're getting an error,
Then you can read one
or more characters
from the stream and
then read to the end of
the line and then you can read
all lines to the file
using read lines,
So if I run this code,
remembering this is the file we had,
this is the end of the first line,
second line and third line,
So if I run that code,
what you're going to see is,
and I'm just going to make
this a little bit easier
for you to see the
whole thing at once,
So is it readable?
Yes, True, So that's a good sign,
That's probably why the next few
lines of code actually worked,
It reads one character T,
and then read to the end
of the line, it continues,
it doesn't reread the T,
it continues from where we left off,
it is the first line of the file,
Then when you see do the read lines,
it continues again from where it left
off and reads the second
line of the file,
You'll see the new line show up as
a newline character and then
the last line of the file,
so you can see all the
values that get returned,
Now, what if I want
to write to a file?
This also comes up a lot
in different scenarios,
Well then we have to create a
file and open it for writing,
So this will actually create the file
for me because the file
doesn't exist yet,
Again, we might want to just
make sure that the file was
created and its writable
before we start writing to it,
So I'm just going to do a
quick test and check if
the file stream is writable
before I start writing,
Then I can write a single string,
I can write multiple
strings using write lines,
So write, you pass a string
that you want to write,
write lines allows you to pass in
multiple strings and if
you want a new line,
you actually need a
newline character,
I'm just going to comment
this part out for now,
and we'll come to that
in just a second,
So if I run this code,
save those changes, go down
here and run the code,
What's going to happen? It says, yes,
I can write to this file and over
here on the left, look at that,
it's created the output,txt file and
inside it you can see hello
world because I wrote
the H and then I wrote
E-L-L-O and then I
said now write a space and now enter
a world and then it inserted
in nice new line for me,
Now, what's really cool about using
write lines is you can pass it
multiple strings and if you
have something like
a list object maybe,
anything that you can iterate
over that contains strings,
you can actually use
write lines to say take
all the strings in that object that I
can iterate over and
write that to my file,
So I can say take the names
Susan and Christopher,
I could have that in a Python
list for example and I can
write but all the names in the
list to the file in one step,
I don't have to write
a loop to do this
it's such a slick little feature,
So now if I write this
again, run this code again,
and now we open output,txt,
you'll see Susan and
Christopher written out,
so both the names are written,
Now, this is where I'm going to
give you a little extra,
a little cool thing,
because a lot of times
when you're iterating
through all the values in the list,
you might want each value to
appear on a separate line,
So I'm going to show you
a little trick that
will help you do that,
One of the things you can do is,
and I'm just going to start on a
new line before I write Susan,
Christopher is you can
use the join command,
So when you're doing the right lines,
you join a new line for each name,
Now you could easily do
commas if you need to
make comma-separated
variable lists and so on,
but in this case, I want each
name to be on a new line,
So the join command allows me to,
after each value, include
a new line with it,
So now what you're going to
see is in my output file,
Susan and Christopher show
up on separate lines,
So that's a neat little trick
that might make your lives
easier when you're iterating through
a list and using write lines,
I just want to finish
off by showing you
another neat trick when using seek,
When you are writing to a file stream
and you write to a file stream,
remember you're not actually
writing to the file,
you're writing to a file stream,
So you can actually move up and down
around the file stream
as you're writing to it,
So if I decide to write the word
demo with an exclamation mark,
and then I use the seek command,
seek allows me to reposition
where I am in the file stream,
So making seek zero literally
moves me to the beginning
of the file stream,
So then if I write again,
it'll actually overwrite
the first few characters
with this new word,
So if I run that code so you can
see how it shows up in the output,
Now we see this manage,txt,
You can actually see that the
word demo exclamation mark,
the first four characters were
overwritten by that word cool,
but it's still kept that exclamation
mark from the word demo,
So Seek allows you to go back and
overwrite parts of the stream,
I do just want to take a minute here
to talk about flush and close,
I explained this in the slides,
So if you've already heard it
there don't need to listen for,
Those of you who jumped to the code
because I know some of
you like to do that,
flush what it will do is it will take
the contents of the file stream
and write it to the actual file,
So that way if there's
anybody else out
there who's opening that file,
they will actually see
your changes as well,
Once you run that flush command,
anyone else opening the file
will see those same changes,
But it doesn't actually mean
this necessarily saved to disk,
the operating system will
decide when to actually
save those changes to disk itself,
So just a small thing to be aware of,
You don't have to call flush
explicitly when you call
the close command to close
your file and that's
something very important,
you always want to close your
files when you're done with them,
file streams when
you're done with them,
that will automatically
do a flush for you,
So not a lot of reason to
call flush explicitly,
but it's a very common
point of confusion,
So I just wanted to
explain what it does,
Basically doing a
flush by itself means
take the contents of file stream
buffer right into the file,
doesn't mean it's saved to disk
yet, just means in the file,
So if anybody else is
opening up that file,
they'll see those changes and it just
empties out the file stream
if it's getting big,
All right, So some cool new things,
Now you're ready to go,
Start working with files,