>> Welcome back for more
Python for beginners,
That probably the number one
request that Susan and I
got after putting together the
last set of videos was well,
for more videos and so
that's what we want to
do here is give more videos,
So we want to start off like we
did last time with a
couple of questions,
So who are we, who are you,
and what is it that we're
going to be doing today?
So let's start here,
Susan, who are you?
>> Well, if you've watched
the introduction to Python
videos and hopefully you have,
if not, go back, check them out,
My name is Susan Ibach,
I also go by hockey geek girl,
By the way, that is
Susan Ibach with a B not
Imac which I saw a several people
on YouTube commenting about,
When I'm not in front of a keyboard
playing around with code and data,
I'm also a mom,
a marathoner and a thrash metal fan,
>> Yeah, I'm Christopher Harrison,
I'm a longtime geek,
I'm a program manager inside of
academic ecosystems
here in Cloud and AI,
I have a propensity to
tell bad jokes as well
as a propensity to say
the word propensity,
I'm a husband marathoner,
and father of a four-legged child,
also known as a dog,
She is an adorable,
about a year and a half mastiff mix,
So yeah, So then who are you?
Well, the target audience for
this course is somebody who
has gone through that Python for
Beginners course and is well,
looking for more
Python for beginners,
that was really it,
That Python is
obviously a huge topic,
we weren't able to get through
everything the first time,
We are going to be assuming
that you have some level
of Python knowledge,
If you don't, go check
out the other videos
first before coming back to this one,
If you've already done that,
or maybe you like, "Hey,
I'm really curious about, say,
the with statement or
I'm really curious
about multiple inheritance," then you
can just dive in and go choose
those particular videos,
>> That's right, You
don't have to follow
this particular set
of VOC sequentially,
There's a few that for example,
it helps to look at the classes video
before you look at
multiple inheritance,
but you don't have to do every
single module of this series,
So this one is designed such
that if it's something
you really want to learn,
you can jump into one directly,
>> Exactly, Yeah, So probably
the most common question
that we got was,
"Hey, what about this?
What about that?
Can we see coverage of this?"
That really is what it is
that we're trying to do here,
So we want to help
empower you even more,
We want to give you more
tools for your toolbox,
that old saying, if the only
tool you have is a hammer,
everything looks like a nail,
That really that same thing
here that we want to show you
some additional things that
you can do with Python,
So that way if you decide,
"Hey, I want to dig
a little bit deeper,
that maybe I want to
start looking at Django,
near and dear to my heart,
" or something like that,
that hopefully you'll be able to
look at even more quickstarts,
even more tutorials, and understand
what it is that's going
on with that code,
>> Yes, Just trying to build
your confidence and answer
some of the questions
you gave to us and
requests that you gave to
us after the first series,
>> Yeah, So with that,
let's get in and start coding,
>> Yeah, Time to have some fun,