>> So now let's talk about how
we can clean up with With,
No, that is not a typing mistake,
I'm actually going to talk
about how you clean things
up with the command With,
When we work with things like files,
so we can come up with
other objects too,
you getting this sort of habit,
there's a basic pattern,
You open the file stream,
you write to the file stream,
you close the file stream,
and then you might see that
with other objects as well,
maybe something like a
database connection,
It's really, really important when
you're done working with an
object that you close it,
because if you don't,
the next time you run the code,
you tend to get error
messages when you
try to open something
that's already opened,
So as a result,
you end up always writing your
code or you should be writing
your code using a nice try
and finally to say, hey,
try to open the file and write to it,
but if something goes wrong,
like I don't have the
permissions or the file,
if I'm trying to read a file,
the file doesn't exist,
lots of things can
go wrong with files,
What if it doesn't work?
Well, if I get an error,
I still need to make sure I close it,
So I use a try finally,
so that if it goes well,
it opens and writes to the
file, then it closes it,
If however, I try to open a
file and something goes wrong,
I still close it,
This is absolutely so important
to avoid errors the next
time you run the code,
because leaving things open really
messes stuff up down the blade,
So what we can do is there is
a really fantastic
command called With,
What it will do for you is it
basically will take care
of closing for you,
It's designed for these objects
where we always want to
remember to close it,
but some of us don't always remember
to do that right in our code,
So I can simply say, hey,
when we do With an open command to
write to this file as a stream,
when we do it right,
this will basically say,
hey, if that goes successfully,
close when we're done,
If that gives me an error,
So this two lines of code is the
same as a whole try and finally,
So this is a wonderful
feature, highly recommended,
really good practice when
you're working with any object
that has a requirement
that you close it when you're
finished working with it,
Now, let's take a look
at that in some code,