>> Let's talk a little bit
about asynchronous operations,
Now this is a really big topic
and there's an awful
lot that goes into it,
Now just like before,
we're going to stick with the tack
that we've taken up until now,
which is we're not going to get
really deep into the concept here,
There's an awful lot
that's written on
asynchronous programming and
specifically async await,
which is what we're going
to be taking a look at,
If you've done say, C Sharp
or JavaScript or TypeScript,
I love TypeScript, you've very
likely experienced async await,
They're really common
in those environments,
Well, JavaScript becoming more
so than it was in the past,
and so what we want to
do here is take a look
at how this is done in Python,
So I'm going to start off a
little bit by talking a bit
about what asynchronous
programming is all about,
We'll take a look at
asynchronous example,
and then we'll get in and see how
we could do that asynchronously,
and the performance improvement
that we're going to
wind up getting here,
So the long and short of it is
the fact that the waiting
is the hardest part,
That certain operations just
take a little bit of time,
Maybe I'm making a web
call, I've got network IO,
I'm doing some fancy
processing, whatever it is,
We don't want to stop everything
just because one operation
is taking its own sweet time to do
whatever it is that it's doing,
Now this basic concept of being
able to execute some bit
of code or being able to
mark our process as sleepable while
something else happens maybe
outside of our app or otherwise,
all of that falls under
this very large umbrella of
concurrency and parallelism,
Again, this is a really broad topic,
We're not going to get
real deep into it at all,
This is basically the main
slide that we have on this,
and what I want to
highlight is the fact
that really any programming language,
any framework, is going to have
some level of options that
you'll be able to take
advantage of when it
comes to concurrency and parallelism,
Python is no exception,
That we have a lot of
different ways that we could
actually spin up threads,
that we can go ahead
and do locking to make
sure that values aren't
changing unexpectedly,
or that if we go in
and change a value,
that we're not going to
mess somebody else up,
something else up, etc,
What we're going to do with
our demo is we're going to
focus in on probably the
most common scenario,
which is a web request,
Because just HTTP or HTTPS,
it's a heavy protocol,
So just having to wait for that
request to go up, to come back,
just the buildup and the tear-down of
that connection in and of
itself takes a little while,
So it'd be nice if we
could go ahead and mark
our application as the
fact that it's going to be
running this or maybe be able
to just do something else
while that long running
operation is taking place,
In Python, starting with Python 3,4,
we got this asyncio module,
What this is going to do
is it's going to graft or
bring asynchronous
development into Python,
Asyncio is going to give us
all the usual suspects when it comes
to doing some form of
asynchronous programming,
It's going to give us
asynchronous streams,
it's going to give
us the ability to do
synchronization or
locking, unlocking,
It's going to help us out an awful
lot with exception management,
that one of the things that
can get really tricky really
quickly is if I'm creating
another thread and that
thread throws an exception,
how am I if I'm sitting over here
know what's happened over there?
So making sure that our exceptions
bubble out appropriately,
All of that is really important and
the asyncio module is going
to take care of that for us,
The big thing that it's
going to do is it's going
to give to us async await,
Let's talk a little
bit about async await,
So here's a big block of code here,
and what I want to focus in on is
a couple of really
important keywords here,
The first is going to be await,
What await is going to do is it's
going to logically pause our code,
That the next line of code here,
this little line of code,
let's just go ahead
and number that as,
let's just say the number three here,
There we go, So our third
line of code there,
that's not going to execute
until the operation
up above completes,
So if we stop and we look at this,
this looks very synchronous because
that's normally the way
that our code works,
That normally what happens,
we have line of code
gives us a value,
line of code gives us a value,
We're all used to that,
That's normally the way
that our code behaves,
What's happening here
though is different,
It looks a little subtle,
but it's different in a very big way,
That while yes, by my
putting in that await,
I'm blocking execution here,
Something else kind of
magical is also happening,
I'm now telling my code,
hey, we're now going to
be waiting on something,
So A, the runtime is going to be
able to go off and potentially
do something else,
So that way if it needs
access to the process,
it can do that,
But also, B, is I can start
a long running process,
start another long running process,
maybe start a third
long-running process,
and then go, okay,
now I need that first value back,
That's exactly what's going
on up above right here,
So what I want you to notice
right here is I'm creating
two items here called two
task, and three tasks,
I'm creating what are known as tasks,
In fact, you can see right here off
of asyncio that I'm
calling exactly that,
I'm calling a task,
Well, what's a task?
A task is really like a
promise, it's an IOU,
It's basically me
setting up a method,
That method is going to
execute and when it finishes,
it's going to get back to me,
So basically what I'm doing
here is I'm saying, hey,
go do this thing,
and when you're done doing
this thing, let me know,
So promise me that you'll
let me know and it goes yep,
I promise I'll go ahead
and let you know,
Then it starts going off
and doing its execution,
So what is it actually doing?
Well for us, it's calling
this little function
that we'll analyze in just a
second here, called load data,
Now as the name implies,
it's going to load data,
Loading data sometimes
takes a little while,
So it's going to go off and
it's going to load up our data,
It's going to execute some
long running operation,
We're going to set this up as a task,
So now both of those you're going
to be running off to the side,
They're going to be
doing their own thing,
Then I can keep executing code,
You'll notice that
right here I've got my
little doing work because that's
exactly what's happening,
is I create those tasks,
I know there are running,
I trust them, They made me a promise,
We're all good there,
we're all buddy-buddy,
So I know those are
doing those things so I
can now focus in on other things,
So I don't have to stop
just because I know that's
going to take a little bit,
Then once I'm finally ready
to go get the answer,
So I told them, hey,
go load some data,
Now I'm actually ready
to get that data,
So now I can go ahead and grab
that data by using that await,
So now what that's going
to do is say, all right,
stop here, wait until
we get a response back,
Then we're going to put
that in two, in our case,
this little two results and
this little three results,
Now the other thing that you're
going to notice here is the fact
that we're doing a
little bit of timing,
You're going to notice that
down at the very bottom,
we've already got the output
there that it's going to tell us
that the operation took 3,4 seconds,
Okay, well, why is that significant?
Well, the reason that
that's significant
is load data is going to be
calling an endpoint that just
pauses for X number of seconds,
X in our case is going to be 2 and 3,
So that first one is going to
be 2 that second one is 3,
So if this would have
occurred synchronously,
this would have taken a
total of five seconds,
Two plus 3 equals 5,
In our case, it took 3,4,
The reason that it took 3,4, well,
you're going to notice right here
that we've got our three
second delay here,
So it's taking at
least three seconds,
It's taking a little bit more
than that because, again, HTTP,
heavy protocol takes a
little buildup a request
little bit to tear that down,
Last little thing that I want
to highlight on this screen,
and then I wanted to take
a look at load data,
is this little
[inaudible] right here,
this little async thing right here,
You're going to notice that
there's one right up above,
So what is an async doing?
Well, async is saying, hey,
in this construct we're
going to call await,
What that also in turn means is
the fact that somebody
else is going to call
this function can also
await on whatever the
operation is inside of here,
If you're going to use await,
it always has to be inside
of an async construct,
So you'll notice in
this case here that
it's inside of that little function,
If we take this one step further,
if we go take a look
at that load data,
now what you're going to notice is
that load data was flagged as async,
Again, what that now means is that
I can say something
like result equals
awaits load data and then
my session variable,
and then whatever the
delay happens to be there,
So now again, my code
is going to pause here,
I'm saying, hey, this is going
to be a long running operation,
So now my process is free to do
other things until we
get the value back,
But again, logically, my code
is going to pause right here,
It's not going to go beyond that
until that returns back a value,
So this little async await is
going to give us that ability,
It gives us a very clean way to
go in and set up
asynchronous programming,
Now you're also going to notice
in this code here that there's
a couple of other libraries
that we're pulling in,
We're calling out to some
external endpoint and so forth,
I want to tie all of that together,
But I think the best
way to tie all of that
together is to actually go
take a look at the code,
So we've seen the slides,
we've explained the concept,
So async means that I can
await on that function,
and I can also put
awaits inside of there,
Await means, hey, we're going
to logically pause code here,
wait for a response to
actually come back,
But our process is still free to
do other things if it so desires,
It gives us again that nice clean way
to go ahead and set up
asynchronous programming,
Again, I think we go in,
take a look at a code,
take a look at
asynchronous comparison
here that will hopefully
help bring it all together,
So let's go do that,