>> Okay, Well, thank you very
much for making it this far,
I do want to apologize for
any bad jokes that we
might have delivered here,
But otherwise, hopefully
you've picked up a couple
of new little tips and tricks
with regards to Python,
>> Yeah, Now that you've had
a chance again to look
at some new features,
the big thing to do
is to practice it,
otherwise, you're going to
forget what you've learned,
That's the best way to reinforce it,
So you want to go out,
find some quickstarts,
read some tutorials, and get
in there and try out some of
the things you just learned,
>> Yeah, Right along those lines,
we've actually got some quickstarts,
and tutorials are ready for you,
that if you go check out the
GitHub repository on there,
you're going to notice that we've got
all level links into
both the documentation,
as well as to a lot of new
little Microsoft learn modules,
some various quickstarts, and
other tutorials that
you can work through,
that are really a great next
logical step from here,
I don't know, maybe we'll be back,
maybe we'll do another set of videos,
>> We just did more Python beginners,
maybe somewhere down the road
will need even more Python,
So meanwhile, happy coding,