>> One of the things
that you will very
likely be doing as you continue to
create and build more code is to
maybe update something inside
of an open source project,
Or maybe you are now part of a team
and you're going to be sharing
your code out with your
teammates and so forth,
So as part of that,
you really want to make sure
that you play well with others,
so to speak, that you become
part of the community
and follow along with some
good community standards,
So that's really what we
want to talk about here in
our formatting and linting section,
So first up, let's highlight this,
Everything that you see on the
screen is in fact valid Python,
All of that will run
just fine the way
that it is, no updates needed,
But take a look at that,
It's not really readable
code, it's not pleasant,
It's well, quite frankly,
it's annoying, it's clunky,
You're going to notice that
we have all various issues,
that we've got inconsistent
use of whitespace so
that in certain areas we've
got spaces here and here,
but we don't have a space here,
You're going to notice
that we've tabbed in to
varying levels here and so forth,
You'll also notice that we've got
inconsistencies when it
comes to "things like that,"
All of those different
odds and ends are things
that can make your code
more difficult to maintain,
and they're also going
to potentially create
issues when you go to share this
code out with your teammates,
other developers, or
potentially the community,
So in the end, formatting matters,
That it's going to make
your code more readable,
It's going to help everybody
else that you're working with,
and it's also going to
make it easier to debug,
In all of my time,
one thing that I've noticed that are
constant is the developers
that I see that are
struggling the most to fix
so many bugs are oftentimes
the same developers who
don't spend an awful lot
of time worrying about
what their formatting is,
or put another way, don't
have consistent formatting,
I'm not quite sure if there's
causation or correlation there,
but there's definitely
something there,
So formatting does matter,
So taking a little bit of time
to make sure that you've made
the decisions about
how you want your code
to look is going to help you out,
That honestly, when I'm writing code,
I'm very rarely thinking about
how I want to format the code,
The reason for that is,
I've made the decisions
on how I want my code to
look so all I'm doing is
just executing that plan,
That way when it comes up
where there is maybe a
decision to be made,
that maybe I'm calling
a function or a method,
and I've got a lot of parameters and
maybe I'm doing a couple of
other things as part of that,
and I'm trying to figure out, ''Okay,
well, do I tab into here?
Do I tab into there,'' and so forth,
I can focus in on those
decisions when those matter,
More importantly, by having
made my formatting
decisions in advance,
it allows me to spend a lot more
time focused in on what it is
that I'm building and a lot less
time on how it is that my
code is going to look,
Because again, I've already
made those decisions,
Now when it comes to Python,
there's this little
proposal called PEP 8,
or Python Enhancement Proposal 8 that
is 100 percent about formatting,
If you go check out the Python site,
we'll link to it inside the GitHub,
you're going to notice that it's very
exacting when it comes
to formatting in Python,
Now I'm not going to go through
every single rule
that makes up PEP 8,
but I do want to highlight a
couple of very common ones,
So first step spaces, not tabs,
I'm not going to get into
the middle of that debate,
Spaces, not tabs, I will
say in Visual Studio code,
when you hit the ''Tab'' button,
it will replace it with spaces
so you're good to go there,
but it is spaces not tabs
when it comes to Python,
Variable name with underscores,
and not either camel or Pascal cased,
So we want that first one,
not the last two,
You also want to avoid
extraneous whitespace,
So what I want you to
notice here is we've got
a space there between the
colon and the number 42,
That's good because there's no space
right after the word
good, That's good,
You're going to notice that
we've got a space here,
and a space here that's
extraneous whitespace,
or more specifically, it's
the space that's right there,
That's the extraneous one,
That's the one that we want to avoid,
Now you're going to notice
again that there's a
whole bunch of rules,
and chances are you probably not
going to remember all of them,
I'll be honest, I don't,
This is where a tool like
linting comes into play,
A linter,
which you're going to notice
basically every language has,
is going to be there
to help support you
when it comes to all these
different types of issues,
So things like naming,
things like spacing, etc,
Now you will need to
install a linter,
Pylint by far being the most common,
you'll notice that we
can install that just by
using the PEP command,
and then away we go from there,
We are going to see when I get into
the demo here in just a moment,
that this is automatically runnable
inside of Visual Studio Code,
I also want to mention
the fact that you
can set up a configuration file,
So that way, if maybe there
are certain rules that
you want to ignore,
certain rules that you want to add,
that you can go ahead and do that,
You'll even actually notice
if you dig deeper into this,
that you can even ignore rules
for just one line of code,
I do want to recommend, however,
that you avoid doing that,
The word that we're looking
for here is exception,
We're looking to make an
exception to the rule,
If we're doing that constantly,
it's now no longer an exception,
it's now just well, the rule,
So if a linter is yelling at you
because you have
poorly formatted code,
the suggestion is to
make sure that your code
complies with the rule rather
than avoiding the rule,
It's just going to
make your code, again,
that much more readable,
that much more maintainable,
Speaking of making your code
more readable and easier to use,
we have this little thing called
a document string or a docstring,
Now what I want you to notice is,
we've used three quotes here,
Three quotes can be used to create
a multi-line string
literal inside of Python,
But if you're not,
say passing this into
a parameter or setting
that to be a variable,
it now becomes what's
known as a docstring,
effectively a multi-line comment,
If you put this at the
top of a construct,
such as a function in my case,
or maybe a class,
it now becomes a document string,
Now what I want you
to notice is the fact
that I've got a little description
of what it is that
this is going to do,
I've got a little section for
my parameters where I'm listing
off all the parameters,
Then last but not least,
you're going to notice that I've
specified the return value,
What's really nice about
putting them in a docstring
is when I'm using a tool
like Visual Studio Code,
that it's automatically
going to then display
this in the IntelliSense
as part of my function,
So when I bring up this function,
I'm now going to see that docstring,
It makes it so much
easier for somebody
else to use the tools
that you've created,
The last little thing that we want
to highlight when it comes to
helping out our users is dealing
with weakly typed languages,
What you're going to notice there
is that that is valid code,
But if we spin this forward,
if we actually ran this,
we're going to wind up
getting an error message,
Because we passed an integer,
we tried to add an
integer to a string,
Python doesn't really like that,
So what went wrong here is we
passed in the wrong data type,
Now we can oftentimes avoid
this or help people avoid this just
by using good parameter names,
Let's be honest here,
if you see name,
you shouldn't be passing
in a number almost always,
Names implies the fact
that it's a string,
But what happens if maybe we
don't have a really clear
variable name for some reason,
or maybe we also want
to be able to indicate
what it is that this
function is able to do,
This is where type
hints come into play,
Now type hints are
relatively new in Python,
You are going to notice that
they're not commonly used,
but I'm a huge fan of them,
especially because of the fact that
I also do an awful lot of TypeScript,
If you've done TypeScript,
a lot of this is going
to look very familiar,
So what we're going to see
here is the fact that we're
now indicating that my name
here is going to be a string,
and we're also going to indicate
the fact that we're going
to return a string,
Again, when Visual Studio sees this,
when Visual Studio Code sees this,
it's automatically going
to pop all of that
up inside of my IntelliSense,
Let's see how we can
take advantage of
Visual Studio Code to do linting,
and how we can use both docstrings
and type hints to be able
to get a little bit more information
about the functions that
we're going to be calling,