>> Let's see linting inside
of Visual Studio Code,
So what I want to highlight,
I'm going to hit "Control
Shift" key here is the fact
that over here, I'll slide on over,
There we go, that we have the
ability to enable linting,
Obviously you can set
that to be on or off,
You can tell it,
"Hey I want you to
run the linter now,"
You're also going to notice
the fact that we have
the ability to select a linter,
Now if you check out the
Visual Studio Code docs,
what you're going to
notice is the fact that
the linter that they've
enabled here or I should
say the settings that
they've enabled on
the linter are relatively low-level,
let's say, that it's
not going to give you
warnings on every last little thing,
So you'll notice, for example,
that sometimes on spaces,
I mentioned before the
no extraneous spaces,
that by default Visual
Studio Code is not
going to give you errors about those,
That's fine, You can go ahead and
decide the level to which you
want to turn on the linter,
You can go in and set up
your configuration file,
But I do want to show
you this in action,
So I'm going to just real quick here,
say X equals 42 and I'm going to
put a semicolon at the end there,
So that way you can see what happens,
When I hit a carriage return,
you're going to notice
that that turns to red,
But I'm not getting any
actual error message here,
But when I save,
that's when my linter's going to run,
Now you're going to notice right
here is my little yellow squiggly,
If I hold my mouse over that,
now you're going to
notice that it tells me,
"Hey, you have an
unnecessary semicolon,"
So now what I can do is
I can get rid of that,
If I hit "Save" again,
now you'll notice that
the squigglies go away,
So it's that's save that will
automatically run the linter for me,
Now one big thing that linters
can really help you
out with is if you had
something like this where maybe
I create a function and I
say return some word there,
and then I say print hello,
The catch that I have here,
the problem that I have
is the fact that print
is not going to be reachable,
That I said return, then I put
something underneath that,
One of the things that I
find myself very commonly
doing is messing up
the end of a function,
I'll openly admit this,
that I'll forget to return
a value or I'll put a
return to the wrong spot,
I do weird things,
Suddenly because of
the fact that I'm so
focused in on the code that
I'm writing and not always focused,
or I should say the problem
that I'm solving and not
always focused in on the
code that I'm writing,
So it will sometimes catch me,
So that's just a couple of the
different things that the linter
can do for me inside
of Visual Studio Code,
Again, you can go in
and configure this,
The other thing that
I want to highlight
here is this little print hello,
Now what I'm going to do is
I'm actually going to get
rid of everything here,
I'm going to sneak down here and
I'm going to say print hello,
When I do this, what you're going
to notice is that IntelliSense
is only able to give me one very
basic piece of information,
the name of the
parameter, and that's it,
Granted for a simple function
like this, that's just fine,
But what happens if you have
a complex function where
maybe you've got 15
different parameters,
It's not necessarily always clear
as to what your parameters
are going to be doing,
Maybe it's not clear based on
your function whether
or not it's going
to have side-effects or
whether or not it's
going to return a value,
This is where those type hints and
that docstring comes into play,
So what I can do is I can say,
"Hey, this is going to be a string,"
I can say, "Hey,
it's going to return a string,"
So now when I go in
and I say print_hello,
now you're going to notice that
my IntelliSense is updated,
Now I can see my parameter
type is a string,
I can also see that it's
going to return a string,
Again, if I add in the docstring,
and I'm just going to do it
manually here real quick,
boom, boom, boom, boom,
Now I can do a real quick
description, returns a greeting,
I can then add in maybe
a parameter section,
So I'll say name,
maybe indicate that this is a string,
and then say the name of the person,
Then I could say returns,
and then I can say the cool message,
So now that I've got that,
let me sneak back down here,
Now let me one more
time, go to print_hello,
Now what I want you to notice is that
the IntelliSense is giving me
a lot of great information,
Now I can see that this is
going to return a greeting,
I can see my parameters and I
can also see the return value,
All of that was enabled
by a docstring,
Now you aren't going to
notice that when we go through
the rest of our demos,
as much of a fan as I am of always
coding with best practices,
you are going to notice we're not
necessarily going to
be using docstrings,
we're not necessarily going
to be using type hints,
This is something where
we should probably all be
in a better habits of that,
But you aren't going to notice this,
especially when it
comes to type hints,
that type hints aren't
really all that
popular yet in the Python community,
For me personally, again,
this me Christopher talking,
I really do hope that
this continues to
grow and continues to catch on that
the big reason that I use
TypeScript as opposed to
JavaScript is for exactly this
reason that I love that typing,
I love being able to
see very quickly,
very easily what's going on,
So that really does help out,
So for our simple little demos,
you're going to notice I'm
not going to put that in,
but I strongly do recommend
for code that you're going
to be writing for real,
that you do go in and
update all of that,
So make sure that
you are putting into
your type hints for
anything that's going to
be called outside of
your application,
especially if you're going to
be sharing this with others,
make sure that you do put
in the docstrings as well,
All right, So that's how
we can use type hints,
that's how we can use docstrings,