>> A need function but it's
sometimes hard to initially
understand in the world of Python
is something called Lambdas,
So to understand it,
let's start by looking
at the types of
problems that Lambdas can solve,
So let's say I want do
something quite simple,
I want to sort some objects
and each object has a couple
of different properties to it,
I have Susan, age 50,
Yes, as of this recording,
that is my age, but it's okay,
I'm cool with that, Great
thing about being a runner,
When you turn 50,
that means you're at the
bottom of your age group,
So instead of being 49 and
running against 40-year-olds,
I'm 50, running against 59-year-old,
So we're the only
people that I know of,
Runners are great because we
don't care about getting
older, It's a good thing,
So I have this list of values here,
Susan, age 50, and
Christopher, age 47,
If I just call sort to
try and sort that out,
I'm going to get an error back
because it doesn't know whether to
sort by the name or
to sort by the age,
So you'll actually get an error
when you try to run this code,
Now luckily, there's a
neat feature with sort,
It can handle the regular
types and strings,
But something complicated like this,
there's something we can do
called the key perimeter,
When you pass in a key parameter,
you can specify a function
that you want to be called
for each element in
the list before it compares
the items for sorting,
So basically it's a
way for you to say,
"Hey, when you're sorting,
call this function, it'll tell
you what value to look
at when you're sorting,"
In our case, we just need to specify,
look at the age or look at the
name or something like that,
So I could, using the Python
skills we learned in the intro
to programming with Python
course, define a function,
So in this case, I've
got a function called
sorter and you pass into it an item,
and that'll be one of the items in
our list and it will
return the item name,
So if I want to sort by name,
I can just specify that
this is the function
that tells you what value
to look at when sorting,
So we have the same list
of values here and when
we call presenters,sort,
we say, "Hey,
use the sorter function
and for each list item,
it will then return the name,"
So now we're effectively
saying sort by name,
Now when we run that
code wonderfully,
it comes back and returns the list of
values and it shows Christopher
first and Susan second,
because Christopher's name comes
first in alphabetical order,
So this is pretty
neat, You know what?
This works just fine,
but it's a pretty small function,
It's not really doing
a whole heck of a lot,
So what Lambdas allow
us to do is if you've
got a function like this with
just a single line of code,
you don't actually have to
declare an explicit function,
You can use something
called a Lambda function,
It's done inline in your code,
So instead of saying
key equals sorter and sorter is
a function declared up here,
I can just say, "Hey,
let's declare that the
key is a function,
and that function is
a Lambda function,"
When you specify a Lambda function,
you specify a parameter item
and the value to be
returned, the item name,
So let me deconstruct that
a little bit for you,
So what we do is before we had
this function called sorter,
which accepted a
parameter item and it
returned the items name property,
When you use a Lambda function,
so your function is, you're just
saying declare a Lambda function,
What you'll see is parameter
item is the same for both,
So the value you specify here maps to
the parameter that you
would have been passing to
the function if you
declare to be explicitly,
The value returned is the value
you specify after the colon,
So this is basically a function,
Lambda function that accepts
a parameter called item
and returns the item name,
Then you can call that,
instead of passing
in a function name,
you can just call a Lambda function,
declare the entire function and
call it all in one line of code,
You can be more clever than that,
Here I've actually modified
the code a little bit,
so it actually returns
the length of the name,
So this would actually sort
by the length of a name,
So in this case, there will
be Susan, then Christopher,
because the name Susan uses
less characters than
the name Christopher,
So Lambda function is
really clever tool,
Not something you have to use,
but it's something you
are going to encounter,
It's a clever trick, It can be
really make for some very clean code,
So let's try that out inside
the actual code itself,