>> Okay, let's take a look at Lambda
functions inside Python code,
That said to understand
Lambda functions,
it sometimes helps
to look at the types
of problems that they can help solve,
So I have here, I've
declared this presenters
list that has both
Susan and Christopher,
it has their name
and their age on it,
but if I tried to sort this list,
I run into a problem because
the sort function
doesn't know whether to
sort by the name or by the age,
So if I actually go
and run this code,
and I know it's going to
fail, hits my filename here,
then you'll actually see
it comes back and says,
"No, you're getting
a type error here,"
It doesn't know how to compare
the two objects because
it doesn't know whether to
look at the age, the name,
The combination of name
and age is just messed up,
So it doesn't know how
to do the sorting,
Now sort by itself actually has
a parameter you can
use to simplify life,
So one of the things you can do
when you call sort is you can
specify the key parameter and
you pass it a function name,
Whatever function you pass to it,
it will basically take
the item in the list,
pass that to the function,
and the function then can
return the value you
want to use for sorting,
So by specifying key
equals sorter here,
it now calls this sorter function,
passes in the first item
in the list; Susan age 50,
and says, "Well for Susan age 50,
the name is Susan, so
sort by name Susan,"
Then it does the same
thing for Christopher,
and it returns Christopher,
So now it knows to sort by the names,
The student's name is Christopher,
So now if I present that sorted list,
let's run this code just to make
sure I'm telling the truth here,
If we call that, you will
see it will successfully
sort the records by name,
So Christopher's shows first
and Susan shows second,
So it successfully done that sort,
This works great and you can
write your code this way,
but now let's take a look at how
lambdas can make this
a little more elegant,
a little more compact,
So I'm going to do
exactly the same thing,
but this time I'm
going to use a lambda,
So you remember we had this
presenters,sort which was
calling with a key of sorter,
which was an explicitly
declared function,
but now I'm replacing that
with one line of code,
I'm no longer declaring a
function that's explicitly named,
Instead, my function is something
called a Lambda function,
A Lambda function is
defined in a single line,
The first value specify is
the name of the parameter,
So this is going to
accept a parameter called
item and it will
return the item name,
So the value you see here is the
value returned by the function,
The value here is the name of
the parameter if it's
passed into the function,
So this is actually doing
exactly the same thing that
our sorter function
was doing over here;
accepting a parameter called
item and returning item name,
But instead of declaring
that function explicitly,
I'm saying make me a Lambda function
with this parameter
and this return value,
When you run it, it does
exactly the same thing,
Just to show that you can do more
than just return a property,
there's actually a
second one down here
where I've declared a
second Lambda function,
but this time I'm sorting based
on the length of the name,
So based on the number of
characters that the name has,
So if we run this code,
what we'll see, just to make a
nice screen start with here,
You'll see the first thing and one is
when we have it sort
it alphabetically,
where our Lambda function was
just returning the item name,
It sorts by Christopher first,
then Susan because in
alphabetical order,
Christopher comes before Susan,
When I sort it by length,
it sorts it by Susan
first because the name
Susan has less characters
in it than Christopher,
So Lambda functions, you can
go for years with Python
and never use them,
but they're very elegant
solution for different types of
code and something you
might want to explore and
something you probably
going to encounter
the more you play with Python,