>> One of the great things about
Python is its flexibility,
that you can really do any type of
development that you
might want with Python,
So for example, you can do
functional programming,
you can do procedural programming,
which we've really actually
already seen quite a bit of,
but we can also do
object-oriented programming,
Now sticking with the tradition of
all the videos that we've done,
I'm not going to spend
really any time talking
about the concepts of classes and
objects and things like that,
But rather, I'm going to
focus in on the syntax and
how you can implement
this inside of your code,
That being said, at a
real quick high level,
a class allows you to define
a data structure that's
going to have some level of
behavior and well, store data,
You create classes to give yourself
some nice reusable
components to be able
to group data and
operations together,
and really just make
your life easier when it
comes to development
in certain scenarios,
Now just to define a couple
of real quick terms,
this is terminology
that's always helped
me when I'm trying to
understand classes,
maybe this will help you as well,
Now here we go, That
a class is a noun,
that this is basically what it
is that I'm trying to describe,
what it is that I'm talking about,
My properties or my
fields are adjectives,
These are the different things
that are true about the class,
Then last but not
least are the methods,
and those are the verbs,
those are the actions,
those are the different things that
this is going to be able to do,
the different things that it's
going to be able to perform for me,
Now to create a class in Python,
syntax looks a little bit like that,
So we say class,
as you might expect, and
then whatever name it is
that we want to give it,
In Python convention is
to use PascalCasing,
For those of you not
familiar with PascalCasing,
let me to do, there we go,
Perfect, and make that
a little bit bigger,
So this is PascalCasing where what
we've got is a capital letter,
and then every word thereafter
is also going to have
a capital letter,
So that's convention in Python,
So create your class and then you can
add whatever it is that you
might want to that class,
Now what you're going
to notice is we're
starting off with a
constructor right here,
Now a constructor in a class is where
I'm going to be able to now
create a new instance of this,
This is how I'm now going to
start to set everything up,
I'm constructing it,
The syntax in Python to set up
a constructor is that
two underscores,
init, and then two
underscores afterwards,
Now what you're going
to notice from here,
I'm now going to set this up
like I would on normal function,
The only real difference
between a constructor
and a normal function is when
this is going to get called,
This is going to get
called when we look to
create a brand new
instance of presenter,
So just like a normal
function in Python,
you're going to notice that
the first parameter is self,
or this if you will in other
programming languages,
That's going to give me access to
the current instance of the object,
After that, we then
go ahead and set up
whatever additional parameters
it is that we might want,
In my case with my presenter,
what I'm saying is,
is I want to be able to set the name,
So I've added that in as parameter,
Now you have to give me a
name if you're going to
set this up as an
instance of the object,
The next thing that I want
you to notice is right here
where I say self,name,
So you're going to notice that I'm
using self and I'm just tagging on,
I'm just appending
on name right there,
This is a little feature
that's part of duck typing,
where what I want to be able to
do is give it something else,
So I'm just giving it something else,
I'm just simply saying self dot,
So I'm actually defining how I
want this object to look on the fly,
This is actually now going to
become what would be
commonly called the field,
Some people might
call this a property,
but a property typically involves
a little bit of code execution,
We'll see that in just a
couple of moments here,
But now I have name that's available
on the instance of
this presenter object,
I'm also going to highlight
the fact that we can
add in any methods
that we might want,
You're going to notice that
I'm going to set up self,
and then I can now read
all of my properties here,
So that's how we can go
in and set up our class,
So we have our constructor,
We can add on any methods
that we might want,
If we want to create a field,
then we just simply create
it almost on the fly,
if you will, inside
of the constructor,
When it comes time to use it,
you'll notice that we call
the constructor much in
the same way that we would
just call a function,
that there is no keyword
new or anything like that,
it's simply presenter equals
presenter, pass in the name,
You'll notice that name field,
we're able to update that on the fly,
So I'm able to just go ahead and
say, name equals Christopher,
Then last but not least,
I'm able to then have
it do this, say_hello,
If I ran this code,
it would then say
"Hello, Christopher,"
Now one of the things
that we have to be
aware of when it comes
to a field is the fact
that anybody is going
to be able to access
that and anybody is going
to be able to update that,
So what happens if we
want to be able to exert
some level of control over how
somebody is able to use our class?
Well, let's start this conversation
by talking a little bit about
accessibility in Python when
it comes to our classes,
At the end of it all,
everything is public,
So if you add on a method,
you add on a field,
whatever it is, it's
going to be public,
There is no protected,
there is no private,
anything like that inside of Python,
What there is, is a
couple of conventions,
If you start something
with a single underscore,
so let's say I said
underscore name for example,
what that means is you
should avoid using
that property or avoid
using that method,
unless you know exactly what
it is that you're doing,
So what I'm saying when
I create a class and
I put in a field or a method
with a single underscore,
is I'm saying yeah, I know that
some people are going to use that,
I want to avoid changing it,
But there is no guaranteed to
the user that it's not going
to change at a later time,
and what I'm trying to
tell the user is, "Hey,
you probably don't want this,
unless you really know
what's going on on
the internals of the class
that I have created,"
The double underscore
means do not use,
This is about as close
as you could get to say
protected or private
inside of Python,
That the double underscore
is going to indicate,
hey, don't use this,
When you go in and you
use something like
the intellisense that's available
inside a Visual Studio code,
what you're going to notice
is that anything with
a double underscore will
automatically wind up
down at the very bottom,
It's trying to hide that,
It's really just trying
to say don't use that,
I would also say that
if you're going to
be using something from a library,
and you see underscores or
double underscores,
follow that convention,
Don't use those items unless you know
exactly what it is
that you're doing and
you're willing to accept the risk
that whatever is there might change,
that it might break your code,
The other thing that we can do
to control a little bit
better accessibility here,
that we can limit what it
is that somebody is able
to do to our class is by
setting up a property,
What a property is going to give
to us is field style access,
but actually using methods
behind the scenes,
So what you'll notice is I've now
updated my little presenter here,
My constructor looks basically the
exact same where I'm
saying self,name,
But now I'm doing
something very different,
Now, name is going to be
set up as a property,
The way that you set up a property in
Python is by creating
the getter side,
So if I said x equals presenter,name,
it's going to give
me this value back,
Then I set the setter side,
which is where if I would say
presenter,name equals some value,
So this right here,
this little getter,
that would be called if
somebody said x equals,
and let's say I had a presenter
called presenter,name,
That's when that's going to execute,
So inside of here,
I can now return back whatever
value it is that I might want,
In my case, it's hard-coded
to be now underscore,
underscore name,
trying to indicate to
the outside world, don't use this,
Now you can also, if you want,
calculate a value on the fly,
that's totally just fine,
So maybe I'm storing
parts of a value,
and now I'm going to perform
some function on it,
now I'm going to give that
back to you, totally cool,
So it doesn't have to just be a
field that you're returning here,
On the setter side,
this is going to be called if
somebody said presenter,name equals,
and it'll say Christopher,
just like that,
So now what will happen is,
is the value, this little
Christopher right out here,
that will now become
part of the name,
So this gives me an opportunity
to run some validation,
So if I want to make
sure maybe that it's not
an empty string or that it's not
null or something like that,
I can go ahead and check
that out there to go
ahead and throw an
exception as needed,
If it all works, then
I could go ahead and
set that value into the field,
To close all of this off,
we can see this in action by saying,
presenter equals presenter
Chris, setting the name,
and then printing out that value,
Now what I want you to
notice is the fact that my
presenter,name equals Christopher,
me reading presenter,name,
To the outside world,
that looks just like a field,
But behind the scenes,
we're actually calling a function,
I think the best way to figure
all of this out is to actually
see it, So let's go see it,