>> Let's go ahead and
create a basic class,
So again, the way that we
define a class is by using
the keyword class here
and then give it a name,
So I'm going to say
"Presenter", just like that,
Now, I can go ahead
and start defining
all of the functions and whatever
else it is that I might want,
Most commonly you're going to
start with a constructor here,
So I'm going to go
ahead and just simply
say def and then underscore,
underscore, and then init,
and now you'll notice
that Visual Studio
is automatically going
to help me out here,
that I just hit "Tab" and then it
just gave me this auto-complete,
Which can be helpful sometimes,
for right now though I'm not
already worried about
what's going on there,
So I'm just going to do a
little bit of clean up and I'm
going to add in that
name parameter there,
So now I'm going to say
self,name equals name,
and I'm going to add in
my little say hello,
so def say hello
self and then we'll go ahead and
say print and then self,name,
Cool, So now, I'm ready to
actually use this presenter
class and the way that I'm going
to use this is by saying
our presenter equals,
our presenter passing the name,
I'm going to say "Chris," Of course,
if you know me at all, you know that
my name is in fact Christopher,
So let's go ahead and fix
that mistake, just like that,
and now let's go ahead and run
presenter and say
hello, boom-boom, cool,
So now that I've got all of that,
let me go ahead and run
this little sample,
So let me change directories where
all my directory zero
three, there we go,
Just do a little bit
of clean up there,
Okay, now in the right directory,
So now let's go ahead and say
Python and then my basic class,py,
and where you're going to notice is
that it prints out Christopher,
Again, the reason that it
prints out Christopher is
because my say hello is going
to print out that name,
and of course I went ahead
and set that right there,
If I didn't have that line of code,
we'll just go ahead
and comment that out,
Well, we run everything,
and now you're going to notice
that it will just print out Chris,
So just prove the fact that
it is grabbing that from
the constructor and setting
that inside of the object,
Now, let's turn our
attention to a property,
So I've already got all
the code are written out,
So that way you don't have to
watch me, type everything,
but I'm going to do a couple
of little additions in here,
The first thing that I want you
to notice is in my constructor,
that I'm going to go
ahead and leave you
exact same code as self,name,
but we're actually right
here calling a property,
So we are not going in and accessing
the field behind the scenes,
but rather we're
calling the "Property,"
Very specifically, here
now I'll put this in red,
Just to sort of drive
the point home here,
I am not saying
self,__name equals name,
I'm not doing that,
and the reason that
I'm not doing that
is because as a best practice,
if you create a property,
you should always use the property,
The property is there for a reason,
that the property is going to
be executing some
level of validation,
or maybe it's going to
be updating something,
somewhere else or
it's doing something,
You're creating it for
a reason and if you're
creating it for a reason,
you should always call that property,
That one little bug that
can very easily creep into
your code is calling the property in
some places and not calling
it in other places,
Don't do that, You're just going
to ask for heartache there,
If you set up the property,
always call the property
even though, "Yeah,
I know I'm inside the class,
I can just go ahead and call
that __name," Don't do it,
You're just asking for heartache,
So now I've got my property setup,
Oops, I've got, stop it,
I've got my property setup here,
It's just highlighting that fact
inside of Visual Studio that's fine,
So I've got my property
setup and now I want
to go ahead and define
the getter side,
So again, this is going
to return my value,
You'll notice that this is
going to return my name,
I'm going to add in just a
little bit of code here,
I'm just going to say "Print,"
Then in the getter just to
highlight the fact that,
"Hey, we're inside of there,"
So his will return back that name
and then here's the "Setter,"
You'll notice that
what we're doing here,
is we're setting up a brand new
little attribute right here,
name and you'll notice of course,
that matches up there,
So that's how those two
are being tied together,
While identifying the fact
that this is going to
be a setter and so now,
what I can do is
setup whatever cool validation
it is that I might want,
In my case, I'm just
going to say "Print
in Setter" just like that,
and prove the fact that
we're inside of there,
Now once I get down to my code,
you'll notice I'm going
to create an instance
of the presenter just like before,
One more time, I'm
going to go ahead and
update the name and then finally,
I'm going to go ahead
and print out the name,
So if I run this,
what you're going to notice is the
fact that we are in the setter,
in the setter, in the getter and
then it's printing out my name,
Now you might notice up here
that it's running in
the setter thrice,
So we've access to the setter
side of our property twice,
You might be going
well, wait a minute,
I only see that happening once,
I only see that happening here,
Well remember, we
called the constructor,
If you remember, we had a
big long talk about this,
Up here in my constructor,
I've called the setter there,
Because again, best practice,
if you create a property,
you should always use the property,
So that's how we can set up a class
inside of Python and
that's also how we can
take advantage of properties to get
a little bit more control over
how it is that somebody is
going to use our class,