>> It wouldn't be much of an
object-oriented programming language,
If we didn't support inheritance,
Now, keeping with our theme,
we aren't going to get real deep
into exactly what inheritance is,
but instead I want to
focus in on the concept,
that we could actually spend
hours talking about
what inheritance is,
I'm going to summarize
all of this in one slide,
We'll link to some
additional resources,
if you wanted to dig deeper into
exactly what inheritance is,
What inheritance is, is it's a
generalization specialization,
That what I'm going to do,
is create an is-a relationship,
So if we take a look at
the first example of,
Student is a Person,
Person is very general,
That's you, that's me,
we're all people, we're all persons,
Student is going to be a
specific type of person,
So it's a specialized person,
Same thing then if we bring this
down into a little bit more of
a programming construct
where we've got
SQL connection and MySQL connection,
In both of those cases,
those could be types of
database connection,
The great part about creating
a generalization
specialization relationship,
is the fact that I can then
count on the generalized code,
maybe things like
talking to the network,
and otherwise all being
in that general class,
Then, I can add on
whatever specialization code
it is that I might need,
I'm going to differentiate
this from composition,
which creates a has-a relationship,
So a student has a
class, for example,
so they attend the classes,
or a database connection
has a connection string,
So that connection string might
have the name of the server,
username, password, information, etc,
So has-a relationship,
done with properties,
my is-a relationship,
that's inheritance,
So let's talk a little
bit about this in action,
One thing that we want
to highlight right away,
is the fact that all methods
in Python are virtual,
Which means that we're always
going to be able to override them,
we're always going to be able
to redefine their behavior,
We're going to notice that
we've got the keyword
super to be able to
access the parent class,
We are going to need to do
this in the constructor,
Notice that bottom low line there,
must always call the
parent constructor,
We're also going to
notice that if there's
anything that's going
on in that super class,
some like field or a property,
or maybe even a method,
Then, I might want
from that super class,
then I can go access that by
using that super keyword,
Let's see a real quick
little code example here,
You're going to notice
that just like before,
I've defined a class called person,
Now, I didn't do anything
really fancy here,
I went ahead and set up
the constructor just
like we had last time,
added in the little method
just like we had last time,
That's it, All this code
we've already seen,
Down below is where
I'm going to inherit,
There's a few things that I
want to highlight in here,
First of all, in order
to indicate that you are going
to inherit from a class,
you indicate that parent class
in parentheses right after
the name of the class,
So now, I've got my
is-a relationship,
Student is a Person,
Now, what you're going to notice,
is that I've got my constructor here,
On my constructor,
I'm going to go ahead
and specify all my parameters,
So self just like before,
Then, what I've got is the name,
and in my case, the school,
Now, name actually comes from person,
One of the things that
Python insist sign,
is when you derive from a class
that you are going to need
to call the parent constructor
if there's anything there that
needs to be able to be set up,
So in my case,
I need to set up that name,
So what you're going to notice,
is that I'm going to
call super right here,
Then, I'm going to call that
constructor by saying __init__,
that's going to allow me
to call the constructor,
and then I can pass
that name up there,
So whatever name it is that
you give to the student,
that's actually going to
be passed up to the person
to give me the ability
to set that property up,
Then, anything that's
specific to student,
in my case, the school,
will go ahead and set up,
and then I can add on
additional functionality,
So you'll notice that if I
decided to go ahead and use this,
so I set up a brand new student,
passed in the name, passed
in the school, I said,
"Say hello", I said, "Sing the song",
We would notice that it would then go
ahead and print out,
"Hello, Christopher",
Then, the song of Ode to UMD,
University of Minnesota Duluth,
by the way, not Maryland,
The other thing that you're
going to notice with classes,
is I can do a little
bit of a, what are you?
So I can say, "Hey,
is this in instance of
additional classes?"
So here's that little
variable that I've got,
I can say, "Hey,
are you a student?"
Well, we know that it is,
so it's going to return true,
We would expect that,
You're also going to
notice that we can say,
"Hey, are you a person?"
Well, remember with inheritance,
we're creating an is-a relationship,
Student is a Person,
So this is actually
going to return true,
Last but not least,
I can explore the hierarchy,
So you'll notice that I
can say, is subclass,
is student, a subclass of
person or another
words, does it inherit?
The answer to that question is, yes,
So if we break this down
here, what's going on,
is there is the say hello,
there is the sing the school song,
The other ones down below here,
Let me just real quick arrow
to each one of those here,
The top one is,
is this a student?
It's true because it is,
The next one here is,
is this a person?
Again, that is true because
we inherited from it,
Then, the last but not
least is, is this,
is a student, a subclass of person?
The answer to that is, yes,
because of the fact that we inherit,
Now, it's also worth noting
the fact that in Python,
every single class that you
create automatically
inherits from object,
object being that base
inside of Python,
Now, because of the fact
that we all inherit from
the same base and that base
has some functionality,
we can always override that behavior,
So going back to our prior example,
if we maybe wanted to
override, say hello,
So for our student, maybe it says,
"I am a tired student named,"
Then whatever the name is,
we can go ahead and do that,
We can also override
those functions that
we wind up getting
from that core parent,
You'll notice and we'll
link to the docs inside of
the GitHub repository the
fact that we have a lot
of really neat functions
that are going to
enable some really
nice functionality,
For example, one of the most
common ones, is this __str__,
What this does is,
it can now automatically
convert this to a string,
So anywhere where we need a string,
this can now become a string,
So you'll notice that
what we've done here,
is we've now defined or really
overridden that __string,
When we do that,
and we now go ahead and say,
"Print presenter", it's now
going to print out Christopher,
The reason that it's able
to print out Christopher,
is because we overrode that __str,
That's basically our two string,
So now, Python is going
to know how to convert
an instance of our
object into a string,
So in a nutshell here,
inheritance, it's going to
create that is-a relationship,
We indicate what it is that we want
to inherit from by just simply
going ahead and putting the parent
class inside of parentheses,
We can always override functions,
including the ones
from that base object,
You'll notice that we can always
add on our functionality,
If there's anything from that
parent class that we need,
we can go grab that from super,
Let's go in and take a look at
a demo to help bring
all of this together,