>> Let's start exploring
inheritance and some of
the cool things that we're
able to do inside of Python,
So I've already got a bit of
code already built for us,
What I want you to notice is that
we've got our little person,
just like we've had a
couple of times now,
We're going to go ahead and set up
a little name field and store
that inside of the object itself,
and we're also going to set up
a little method here called,
say_ hello, which will
print out, Hello,
and then the name that we've
stored inside of there,
You're also going to
notice that we're
going to set up a new
class called Person,
or sorry, student, that
will inherit from person,
Its going to have a name
property and a school property,
You're also going to notice
the fact that we're going to
call that parent constructor
to set up the name,
You're going to notice that we're
going to be in charge of the school,
so we'll set that up here,
Then we can add on additional
functionality as we see fit,
So if we go ahead and create
an instance of our student,
then you'll notice that we
can call that say_ hello,
we can call the sing_school_ song,
and all of that will execute
the way that we would expect,
So let's start here,
This is where I want to start,
Just clearing out my screen,
Now, let's go ahead and
say, Python demo,py,
What we're going to notice
is that we get that Hello,
Christopher and that ode to UVM,
which is actually not the school
that I went to, but that's okay,
So that is coming from person,
Remember, that's our say_ hello,
and this is coming from
our sing_ school_ song
and that is on student,
Now, as we've already
mentioned, we can also,
let me just comment out these
two lines of code right here,
do a little bit of
investigative work,
So we can start to see, hey,
is this a student? Just like that,
You know what I'm going
to do? I'm going to use
the cool little formatting function
that's available to me in Python,
I'm just going to go like that,
Boom, So now that will automatically
just print out as appropriate,
Let's go ahead and do the
exact same thing down
here is this a person?
Then boom,
Boom, Boom, Then last but not least,
my little format string,
is student a person?
Then boom,
Okay, I really love this
little format string,
It's something that you see in
many other programming languages,
So that way I can actually just
go curly brace, curly brace,
and then it will just execute
whatever code is inside of here,
What's also really nice
about this is if maybe I had
a variable name in here
and it was returning
back something that's not
a string, Or in my case,
I've got a function
here that it's going
to return back something
that's not a string,
the issubclass, for example,
returns back a Boolean,
It will automatically do a
string conversion for me,
It's wonderful, I love it,
It's a really nice little
Python 3 bit of syntax,
It's great syntactical candy,
Okay, So now, let's go
ahead and run that,
Now, what we're going to
notice is the fact that,
yes, we have a student,
Yes, it's person, and
yes student is a person,
So we created that object right
there and then we went
ahead and we check to see,
hey, student person and
a student is a person,
all of that came back as true,
Okay, Let's keep on keeping on here,
Let me comment out those
lines of code right there
and let me take one real quick
step back to our student,
What I want to do is I want to create
a brand new definition of say_ hello,
Now, you'll notice that
the IntelliSense automatically
gives me say_ hello,
The reason for that is
student inherits from person,
person has that say_hello,
So now, when I hit tab to let
this auto complete for me,
you're going to notice
the fact that it
automatically makes this
call to super forming,
So if I want to as part
of my new implementation,
let the parent class
do some of the work,
or maybe I need to
have it do something,
grab the value and then append
onto it or whatever it
is that I might want,
I have that ability here,
So I can say, hey,
let the parent do some work,
whatever that work might be,
Then I can add on my own,
my own custom code,
and I can say something like print,
oops, I am rather tired,
I feel like changing my quotes
around to put it in the I'm,
So that's going to be just fine,
So I can just say something
like, I am tired,
So that's going to
execute from student,
So let's stop and pause for
just a second here and talk
about what's about to happen
when I run this code,
When I create an instance of student,
it's now a student,
So when I call,
say_hello off of that,
it's now going to do
that as a student,
So it's going to add on that
I am rather tired part of it,
But you're also going to notice
that I can still call the super,
So I'm still going to be
able to say, hi, I'm,
and then whoever it is that it
happens to be, so I'm Christopher,
So we're going to see
both of those in action,
So let's go ahead and run our code,
I'm just going to get rid of
that bottom function here,
So you're going to notice that I'm
going to call that, say_ hello,
So let's go ahead and save this,
So now, let's go ahead and
run that Python demo,py,
Now, what you're going to notice
is that this turning from the parent,
and then this is now
running from the student,
Now, the only reason
that that parent code is
executing is because of the
fact that I told it to execute,
If I take that out
and now I rerun this,
what you're going to notice is
the fact that it just says,
I am rather tired,
So when we override a function,
it's not going to
automatically call the parents
or called the base class,
we have to tell it to do that,
The last thing that
I want to show off
here is that neat little
string function here,
So let's start off by just
trying to print out our student,
So I'm just going to
say, print Student,
So let's see what happens,
So I'm going to run this bit of code,
I'm going to see what happens,
What you're going to
notice is it gives me
back something that's
not overly helpful,
It's telling me the fact
that it's an object,
It's giving me some form of a
memory address, and that's it,
I don't know what to do with that,
It's not overly helpful,
Now, the reason that
it's giving me that is
because Python is just
coded to do that,
If it doesn't know how to
convert something into a string,
it just gives you the class name,
the memory location, and
we're done, Not helpful,
Now, maybe it's helpful
in certain situations,
but the most part it's not helpful,
It'd be nice if I could say, hey,
if somebody tries to
convert you to a string,
this is what I want you to do,
Net is where str comes into play,
So I'm going to say
def__, You'll notice
that it automatically
enlists off things like eq,
and greater than, and less than,
So if you want to enable
that functionality,
you can actually do that right
here, it's pretty slick,
Again, we'll have a link
to all the different
things that you could do,
In my case, I want str,
I need to just return
back a string here,
So I'm going to return back
something a little bit fancier,
I'm going to say that I'm
going to return the name,
self,name
attends and then { self,
school} Much more helpful,
So now when I go ahead and run this,
now what you're going
to notice is that I get
that neat little
string representation,
Now, I want to close all of this
by highlighting a couple
of real quick things,
Number 1, is again the fact
that we've got this
little is a relationship,
Number 2, again, the fact
that everything is virtual,
that I can override whatever
it is that I might want,
The last thing that I want to
highlight is with this str,
Now, there's a little
principle called YAGNI,
Y-A-G-N-I; you aren't
going to need it,
I'm a huge believer in
the YAGNI principle, you
aren't going to need it,
and I will not add something,
I will not add functionality to
my code until I actually need it,
So people will ask
the question, "Hey,
when should I add an str?
When should I add an EQ?"
The answer is when you need it,
So if I'm using a
framework like Django,
or maybe I'm doing some form
of like iterative
development or I'm doing
unit testing where I just
need to be able to real
quickly print something out
and just see what it is,
or I'm giving it to a
framework that needs to be
able to real quickly
convert it to a string,
cool, then go ahead
and implement str,
But if you don't need it,
there's no reason to implement it,
Okay, So that's how you
can do inheritance,
In the next section,
I want to turn our attention
to multiple inheritance
and how we could take advantage
of something called mixins,
but more on that in the next module,