>> So I have a nice
CSV file here and I
want to be able to use this and
accesses with my Python code,
but how do I get to it?
So what I'm going to do is
I'm going to go to Jupyter,
and I'm going to create
a folder so that I
can keep all the data
files in one place,
So over here on the right-hand
side, I can just say,
give me a new folder
instead of a new notebook,
By default, you'll see it
shows up as untitled folder,
So all I have to do is
simply select that and
then there's a rename option
to give it a better name,
So I'm going to call that data,
That's a fairly common name given
to folders where we
restore data files,
Then once I have the folder created,
I simply select that folder and
then I can upload whatever
CSV files I want to use,
So I have this CSV file
with information about all
sorts of different airports,
and I ask it to upload that file,
Once it's uploaded, you
can even see that you have
successfully uploaded your
CSV file into Jupyter,
So now our Python code inside
the Jupyter Notebook is going
to be able to access this file,