>> So as we're preparing
our data to train models,
we do have to make sure that
the data we're working with
doesn't have missing values,
which can cause issues and
actually when you try to train a
model might give you an error,
and we also need to deal
with duplicate rows,
because duplicate rows can skew
the result when you're
training data models,
So now let's take a look at inside
our actual code using Python
and Pandas dataframe methods,
how we can handle missing
values and duplicates,
So taking a look here,
we're still working
with Pandas dataframes,
So I'm going to import
that wonderful Pandas library
and I'm going to start
by loading a nice dataset
here into our dataframe,
which contains all sorts of
information about different
flights with a come in,
left, and arrival delay information,
Now, this is a very big dataframe
and I do not want to go reading
through every single row to find out
which rows might have
a duplicate value,
But fortunately, I can use
the dataframes info method,
What that will do is it will tell me
all great information about
that dataframe and of
the data inside it,
So it tells me things like, "Hey,
you have 300,000 rows inside that
dataframe across 16 different
columns," and it also
tells me for each column,
how many rows contain actual
values, non null values,
So I can see that
flight date has 300,000
rows all containing non null values,
Unique carrier, all the rows
contain non null values,
But when you get to tail number,
you'll notice only about
299,000 of the rows
contain non nulls or
for arrival time,
But again, there's a
number of records here,
Most of the rows have
a non-null value,
but that must mean that some
of them do have a null value,
So this is a simple way to check
and see if you have
any rows which contain
a null value or
any particular columns that contain
null values inside your dataframe,
So now that I've identified I do have
rows with missing values, nulls,
NANs, these words can be used
interchangeably here,
how do I handle that?
So if we go back to our code,
once you've identified it,
you can use the dropna,
What that will do is it will drop
the rows and missing values,
Now, by default, this does not
modify the delays dataframe itself,
Instead, what I'm doing is
I'm saying drop rows of
missing values and take
the remaining rows and put
them into a new dataframe,
So if I run this and then I do
an info on the new dataframe,
you'll see it only has 295,000
rows left because all the rows
with missing values
have been removed,
But you can see that
every single column,
all of the rows
contain actual values,
So I can confirm that I
have successfully dropped
every missing value or every row
with a missing value
from my dataframe,
If however, you prefer not
to create a new dataframe,
if you just want to drop
the missing rows from
the existing dataframe
delays_df, you can do that too,
That's supported, There's a parameter
called inplace equals true,
When you set it to true,
basically that's saying modify
the delays dataframe itself,
So now what I've done
is I've actually
dropped the missing rows
from the delays dataframe,
So you can see once again,
now it only has 295,000 rows,
but every single one of the columns,
all the values in there have
no missing values, no nulls,
The other scenario we sometimes
have to deal with is
duplicate values,
So one of the things you'll find
is sometimes when you're
doing data science set,
data may come in from
multiple files and then they will be
merged together into one dataframe,
So as a result, you can end up with
some duplicate rows and that
can skew results when you
start doing data science,
So one of the things
we need to do is check
if there's duplicates
and then deal with them,
So I'm just going to
import a very small file
here so that you can see
it has duplicate values,
So it has three records from USA,
Those are duplicates, they just
happen to be in the same country,
But here, I can see that there's
actually two records
from Dulles Washington,
Now, I've deliberately displayed
a very small dataframe
here so you can see that,
But what if the dataframe was too
big to just show on the screen?
How could I quickly
just check and say,
"Hey, look at all the rows and
tell me if there's duplicates",
Well, the Pandas dataframe
has this duplicated method,
What that will do is
it'll return a true or
false indicating whether or
not a row is a duplicate
of the previous row,
So in this case, the third row,
this one here too Dulles Washington,
is a duplicate of the previous row,
So you can see that the
one with the index of two,
it says, yes, that row
is in fact a duplicate,
It does have to be the
entire row with a duplicate,
Simply having the same value in
a column does not make
it a duplicate row,
Once you've identified
you do have duplicates,
if you want to get rid of those,
all you need to do is
call drop_duplicates,
I'm using that same parameter
inplace equals true to say
drop the duplicate rows inside
the airport's dataframe itself,
So now when I run,
you can actually see I've
successfully gotten rid of
that extra Dulles Washington record,
You will notice of course,
that index number that can
cause gaps in your indexes,
So just be aware of that as
well when you're duplicating
or dropping duplicate
rows, So there we have it,
We can figure out if we have any
missing values in our dataframe,
get rid of the rows that
do have missing values,
We can determine if we do have
any duplicate rows and we can
get rid of those duplicate rows,
So now, you've got your
data a little more
cleaned up and ready for data
science in training models,