>> So we were just
talking about how we can
use Python to work with
data files like CSV files,
Let's try it from an actual notebook,
So I have here a
notebook in front of me,
and because I want to read the
data into a pandas DataFrame,
because when we're
working with Python,
DataFrames are very
useful for data science,
I'm going to need to import
that pandas library again,
You can get used to that
line of code, I'm thinking,
Let's say I have a nice CSV file
containing airport information,
write the airport's
name, city, and country,
You can actually see that actual
row is in my CSV file itself,
as long with the names,
cities and country for a
number of different airports,
So I can simply use
the Read CSV command
to read that data into a DataFrame,
and then display the
contents of that DataFrame,
So sure enough, you can see that
the column names were read
successfully from the file,
You can see that index values
were created as Christopher
was explaining,
Panda DataFrames, you always
have an index for each row,
In this case, because
it was none provided,
it generated them for me,
So everything looks great,
But when we are writing Python code,
we have to make sure that
that code can handle
different variations in the
data file that we're loading,
For example, I might
have a record here,
wherever row for Heathrow London
has an extra comma in it,
and that extra comma is going
to mess up my code because
it now thinks there's four
values in that row is a three,
So by default, if I just
try to read that file,
it's actually going to crash,
and it won't put any data
at all inside my Dataframe,
Well, I have a couple
of options here,
I can now go digging
through that file,
try to figure out
where is the one row
of that's causing the
error and try to fix it,
Yes, there will be some
hints in the error message
to help you find which
row has the problem,
But one of the neat things
about data science is
sometimes it's okay if
we've got a million rows,
maybe we can leave 12 of them out,
So maybe we just want
to skip the bad rows,
So in that case,
we can use Python
supports that as well,
So what we can do, is we can specify
error bad lines equals false,
That simply means if you meet a
row that you can't interpret,
skip that row to continue,
So if I run this one,
you'll see it successfully
loads the records,
and that record from London for
United Kingdom was simply skipped,
So that record was not loaded,
The other common situation
you'll encounter when
reading data files with
your Python code is,
the file may not contain
a row that tells you what
the column headers are,
So here, I have some data,
but there's no row telling me
what the column name should be,
By default, if you pass this in,
basically Python and the pandas
are going to get a little confused,
because they assume you are
passing in values for
the column headers,
So it reads the first row of data,
and thinks those are
the column headers,
So suddenly, I have a column
header called Seattle-Tacoma,
and Seattle in USA,
So I need to make sure I
have a way of saying, "No,
the first row in the file is
actually data, it's not headers,
"That's why we have the option of
specifying header equals none,
So if I specify header equal
none when I load the file,
that's a way of saying
there's no header row,
and I simply want you to assign
values to those column headers,
If I don't tell then
what values to assign,
it'll just give them a number value,
column 0, column 1, column 2,
Now you might have appreciated when
crystal was doing some queries
against the Dataframe,
that sometimes it's nice to be
able to specify the columns by name,
It's easier for me to remember
that city contains the city,
rather than column
index 1 is the city,
Even if the header values
aren't specified in the file,
you can specify it by
using the names parameter,
what column names you
would like to use,
So if I run this, you'll see
it actually successfully said,
"Oh, you don't have a header row,"
So here, specify a value name,
city, and country for
my three columns,
The other scenario you're most
likely to run into when working
with CSV files or Datafiles in
general, is a missing value,
In this case, I have a data file,
For one of my records,
shuffle in the Netherlands,
there's no city specified,
You just see comma, comma,
Now if you read that,
the way Python pandas will
display a missing value,
is it displays it as NaN,
so not a number, if you will,
So that indicates that
there was no value
found for that particular
value inside the record,
So you'll see that as well,
Now sometimes when you start really
doing a lot of data science,
and you do a lot of cleaning of data,
you'll see that when you look
at data science courses,
once you finish cleaning the data,
you might decide, "Hey, now that
the state is all
tidied up and cleaned,
maybe I'd like to save a copy of it,
so the next time I'm working with it,
I don't have to do as much
cleansing and rework,"
So one of the other neat
things we can do with pandas,
is we can actually write
the contents back out
to a CSV file as well,
So if I have data in
a DataFrame already,
then I can simply say, hey,
let's use to CSV,
and let's write that
output to a data file,
Now, one of the things
that's a little
interesting if I was
to open that file up,
and I'll show it to you in a minute,
is the index values will
be written in as well,
So if I don't want the index value,
that zero, one, two, three,
four to appear in a CSV file,
then I want to specify
when I write the file,
that I want index equals false,
That's a way of saying please do
not include the index values,
So let's go take a look at the
actual data files created,
so you can see the difference
between using index equals false,
or not specifying index equals false,
So here you can see,
here is the file I
created by default,
You can see it added the index
values from the Dataframe,
and you can see when I did
specify index equals false,
that it simply added the row
values itself without an index,
So there you have it, You now have
the ability to use your Python Code,
to move data to and from CSV
files, and pandas DataFrames,