>> So continuing with
the fact that in a lot
of data science courses,
and tutorials you look at,
there's a lot of talk
about preparing data,
One of the other scenarios that
you'll often have to handle,
is handling duplicate rows,
You'll see that data science really
doesn't like it when there's
multiple copies of the same row,
and they also tend to
get upset or crash,
Even can crash code if encounter
rows which have missing values,
So let's see how
Python and the pandas
DataFrame gives us some methods
and techniques for
handling those situations,
Specifically, let's start
with the missing values,
There are many different
data science methods you'll
use which will actually
crash if they hit a row
with missing values,
So if I had the DataFrame
here in front of me
for some airport
information because I have
an arrival time and the
delay time that are
missing values showing
up as that NaN,
This could actually
cause my code to crash,
I won't be able to train a model,
So one of the things
we need is a way of
knowing if a particular
DataFrame has missing values,
The info method of the DataFrame
is fantastic for this,
What it'll do, it'll tell you-all
sorts of great information,
One of the things it'll tell you is
how many rows are in your DataFrame,
Then for each of the columns,
it will tell you how
many of the rows in that
DataFrame contain values
that are not null,
So you can see here that
the flight date, well,
all 300,000 rows contain
non null values,
So there are actual values
at every single row for
the value of flight date
and for unique carrier,
But wait, when I hit "Tail
Number," out of that 300,000 rows,
only 299,000 or so of
them have actual values,
non null values in them,
That means that some of those rows
do contain a null or a missing value,
So you can see here there's
actually three different columns
that have a number lower
than 300,000 with non null,
So that indicates to me there are
some missing values for some of
the rows of this three columns,
So now that I know I have
some missing values,
how can I now use Python
to deal with those values?
Well, fortunately, Python
pandas is designed for this,
so it has a dropna method,
which means dropna those NaN values,
and it allows me to remove
those rows from my DataFrame,
Now one thing to be aware of,
very specific when working
the pandas DataFrames,
When I do a dropna, I have not
actually dropping the rows
from the DataFrame itself,
I am saying drop the
rows and then copy
the DataFrame with the dropped
rows to a new DataFrame,
So here I have this
one row with values,
what it does is it creates
new DataFrame called
delay no nulls DataFrame and
it's missing that row 2,
which had the null values
or the missing values,
If however you want to actually
modify the DataFrame itself,
you can do that by just specifying
inplace equals true and
then what happens is
literally just remove that row
from the existing
delays df DataFrame,
The other scenario we might need
to handle is duplicate rows,
So you will often find that
a lot of times we're
working with data science,
you'll be given files from
multiple different places then
you combine all those files
together into one DataFrame,
That may mean that you
get into situations where
sometimes rows may be
loaded multiple times,
We also want to handle
those duplicate rows
because that can skew results
when you're doing data science,
So here I have some
data in front of me
and some simple information
about airports,
but I have two rows for the
airport in Dulles, Washington,
So how do I handle that
using my Python on my panda,
and Python and Pandas?
We have the airports
DataFrame we call duplicated,
and what that will
do is it will return
true or false for every row,
If a raw locates is
a duplicate of a previous
row, then we'll see a true,
So you can see here that the
first row, it returns false,
second row is false because up
until now it has not seen
a duplicate of Dulles,
The next row is another row,
is exactly the same
so now it says true
because this row is a duplicate
of a previously seen row,
and the remaining
rows were all false,
I also want to make
sure we highlight here,
that it's the entire
row is a duplicate,
We have multiple records
with a country of USA,
but duplicate is looking for records
with the entire row is a duplicate,
So this allows us to
locate duplicate records,
Now, how did we get rid of them?
Well, there's a
wonderful little method
called drop duplicates
and I'm going to
use that same little trick I did
for dropping missing
rows and missing values,
I'm going to use the
inplace equals true to
say within this DataFrame itself drop
the duplicate rows and what
that's going to simply do for me
is get rid of that second
row for Dulles, Washington,
So my data is all set nice and tidy,
ready for me to go on and
play with my data science,
So now we've dropped
our duplicate rows,
We're ready to start going and
doing things like training models,
Now, let's try all of
us out in actual code,