>> So whenever you start working with
data science and you're
working with Python,
at some point, you're going to be
needing to load some data files,
The most common data file format
you'll likely be working with
is a CSV file or a comma
separated variable file,
One of the things we
just want to touch on
is what does that look like and
how do I work with those files when
I'm working inside
of Jupyter Notebook?
So comma separated variable files or
CSV files is extremely popular
format for data files,
So a lot of times when you're
going off and searching for data,
this will be the format it's in,
What you'll see is each
row, the file contains
one record and you'll
have a special character,
often a comma, that's used to
separate the different column values,
The first row may
contain actually the names
of the different columns,
so you know what is
the value in each row,
So you can see here I've got
the name, city, and country,
Then I have the name, city,
and country for a number of
different airports, for example,
So that might be a CSV file that I
might use to analyze inside my data,
Now if you want to use this data
file inside of Jupyter Notebook,
you're going to have to make sure
the Notebook can find
the physical file,
So how do I do it?
Well, I'm going to upload
the files to Jupyter itself,
Now one of the things that's
a really good practice
is to take that file and
create a sub folder,
and most common name for the sub
folder is something like data,
not very original but
nice and descriptive,
So we create a sub
folder called data,
you upload all your files into there,
and then we'll be able to
access it from a Notebook,
So we first have to
create the folder,
and then once we've done that,
there's an upload option
to upload our files,
Let's move over to Jupyter
Notebooks and try that out,