>> Let's see how we can find
certain items inside
of our DataFrame,
So just like before,
I'm going to go grab
our pandas library
and I'm going to set
up our DataFrame,
You'll notice just like before,
we've got name, city, country,
and all of the airports
that are inside of there,
If we want to go find
a specific column,
the simplest way to do this
is just to use that indexer,
So you'll notice that I
pass in the name of city,
and that will give me back
the city just like that,
If I specify country,
then it will, of course,
give me back the country,
It's always giving me
back that index as well,
which honestly I like,
So that way I can always find a
specific row if I need to later,
If I want to go grab
particular items,
then what I'm going to
do is put that inside
of a list as that parameter,
so that's going to give me back
my name and my country here,
You'll notice one more time with
our notebook the fact that
if I just execute the code,
then it will just print
that right out for me,
but again, one of my favorite
little things with notebooks,
If you happen to know the index
location, then you can do that,
So to get whatever the first cell is,
I can do that with 0 ,
0 to go get it over at 2,2
then I can do it that way,
Now most commonly, the way
that you're going to be using
this index location is to go
grab multiple columns
or multiple rows,
So if I want to specify a
range, then I can use that : ,
: that's indicating that I
want all rows, all columns,
Boom, there we go,
If I want to indicate
the start and the end,
then I can do that by using,
in my case, zero and two,
This will give me back
the first two rows,
or in turn, the first two columns,
if I so desire,
If I maybe you want to go grab
the second and the third,
make sure that you
indicate the ending index,
Remember, it's going to go all
the way up to, but not including,
So now what I'm going to get
back is one and two here,
which is what we would've expected,
So it behaves just
like a range for say,
an array or for a list,
If you want to specify
individual items,
maybe I want the first and
the third back column wise,
then I can do that by
specifying that little list
that you see right there,
So 0,2 this is going to
give us back columns 0 ,
2 or the first and the third,
So when I run this, it's going to
give me back name and country,
If I sneak all the way back up
to the top here, there we go,
We'll notice name and country
is our first and third,
so that was exactly what we got back,
If you want to do that same thing,
but you want to do it by name,
then you could use location,
Again, that second parameter
is going to be the column,
so name and country is going to
give me back name and country,
Just like that, we get
the same things,Cool,
So that's a real quick primer,
real quick starting point for going
in and working with our data,
One thing that you are going to
notice whenever you're working with
a DataFrame is that we need
the ability to quickly go in,
find rows, find columns, etc,
Like I mentioned at the outset,
there's a lot of different
ways that we can do this,
This is a couple of very common
ways that you can do it,
Again, we've linked
to the docs inside of
our GitHub page so you could
go off and explore from there,
but there's still
more with DataFrames,
That's what we're going to take
a look at in the next video,