>> As you explore different
data science tutorials
and watch different
data science videos,
one of the things they're
always talking about is
preparing your data and the time
you spend preparing your data,
One of the things you'll
end up doing as you
prepare your data is you're
going to have to either
remove columns from a
DataFrame or you might need to
take some of the columns inside
a DataFrame and move them
into a separate one,
so splitting them off, if you will,
So let's explore how you do that
with the Python code as well,
So in this case, maybe I have
something like the actual
arrival time column,
If I was doing some data
science and I was trying to
predict how many minutes late
a flight was going to be,
that's a value inside
the arrival delay,
Well, if I had the
actual arrival time
and the scheduled arrival time,
well, I can just calculate
arrivals delay by subtracting
one from the other,
But I'm trying to train
a model to look at all
the other factors like,
what airport did it leave from?
What time did it leave in?
How long was the flight?
Use those values to try and predict
if the flight arrived on time,
So I don't just want to say take
the actual arrival time and subtract
the scheduled arrival time,
I'm not really training a model
that's just doing a subtraction,
So in this case, I might need to
remove the actual
arrival time column,
So how do I do that with Python code?
Well, there it is, I'm sure
you're discovering by now,
pandas has some fantastic features,
and the DataFrame object
has a drop method,
So you can simply say
drop a particular column,
So if I say, "Hey,
on my delays DataFrame,
let's drop the column called
actual arrival time,"
But this doesn't actually
modify the delays DataFrame,
It simply returns a
new DataFrame which
contains everything except
the actual arrival time,
So I get a new DataFrame
containing everything
except actual arrival time,
If however you want to make
the change to the delays
DataFrame itself,
you can actually specify
in-place equals true,
and that's a way of saying modify
the DataFrame when
I'm doing the drops,
So that way you don't have to copy
the values to a new DataFrame,
I'm just saying, no, modified
this one right here,
and that will simply drop
the actual arrival time
column from delays DataFrame,
Now, the other thing you might
need to sometimes is you
might need to take
some of the columns
from a DataFrame and move them aside,
One of the most common
things you'll hear
people talk about in
Data Science courses
is the idea of qualitative
data and quantitative data,
So qualitative data
is descriptive data,
things like, what Airport is it?
Are things blue or green or
gold, they're describing things,
But quantitative data
tends to be numbers,
How big is something?
How long is something?
How many minutes the
delay was, and so on,
You'll discover as you
explore data science
that those quantitative values,
training models, they
love that type of data,
So quite often, we have to take
those quantitative values and
pull them aside to use
them to train our model,
So in this case, that's my origin
airport, my destination airport,
So I can simply create a slice of
that DataFrame and kick
back to that module,
Christopher showed you
what we talked about
how to query a DataFrame,
So basically, I'm going to query
the DataFrame to return
just those two columns,
and then take those two columns
and put them in a new value,
So all you do is you do a query,
I'm using loc here,
Remember, that first column means,
which rows do I want back,
and a single column
means return all rows,
and then you specify
which columns you want,
In this case, origin airport
and destination airport,
and take those values and put
them into description DataFrame,
and that will create
this nice new DataFrame
for me with just the
columns that I need,
So these techniques are
going to make it easier for
you when you start having to
prepare your data for data science,
Now, let's take a try
doing it in code,