>> So when you're exploring in
different data science tutorials,
quite often, they talk
all about preparing data,
and one of the things
they'll often talk
about is either needing to remove
certain columns or to move certain
columns into a new DataFrame,
So we're going to look at
our Python code and see how
pandas gives us some neat tools
to make it easier to do that,
So we're still using
pandas DataFrames,
so I'm going to start off
by importing that library,
and then I'm just going to read
a data filling to give
us a starting point,
So I'm reading in some
flight information here,
and if you look at
the first few rows,
you can see all sorts
of wonderful data,
lots of different columns of
information that I
might be analyzing,
Very typical data file,
Now, you might get
into a situation here
where if you look at this,
you'll notice I want to maybe
predict the arrival delay,
which is how many minutes
late a flight is going to be,
Because this data set is so complete,
it actually has the
scheduled arrival time
as well as the actual arrival time,
Well, it doesn't take a machine
learning model to
figure out that if you
subtract the time a plane actually
arrived from when it
was supposed to arrive,
you can just calculate arrival delay,
But if I'm going to try
and train a model to
predict what time future
planes will be landing,
it won't know the actual arrival time
when I'm asking it to predict if
the flight is leaving tomorrow,
So I might need to delete
that arrival time column,
It's unnecessary, it's not going
to help with my model training,
So you will have situations
where you want to delete it,
So if I want to remove
this arrival time column,
fortunately, the pandas DataFrame
has a feature to help me with that,
There is a method called drop,
You tell it which column
you want to remove,
and you can then say, create me
a new DataFrame without
that extra column,
So if I do that, this new
DataFrame I create, you'll notice,
it still has the
scheduled arrival time,
but the arrival time column is gone,
Now, one of the things
you may notice here,
and this is something to keep
in mind when working
with pandas DataFrames,
is it didn't actually
modify delays DataFrame,
it simply created a new DataFrame
without that extra column,
If you want to modify the
delays DataFrame itself,
you can do that, pandas
will support it,
You specify the value
in-place equals true,
and that means modify the
delays DataFrame itself,
So now the delays DataFrame has no
longer got that arrival time column,
So it's up to you, depending on how
you like to work with your code
and what you're doing with it,
whether you wanted a new one
or to modify the existing one,
Now, sometimes we have to
split up different columns,
One of the things
that comes up a lot,
it's said in data science,
is this need to sometimes only have
the numeric values to do
our analysis or only to
look at the string values,
Because you'll discover as
you explore data science,
that there are different
techniques for handling
string values versus numeric values,
So it's not unusual to take
your DataFrame and say, "Hey,
take the values that are more
string or qualitative,
put them in one place,
Take the quantitative
and numeric values,
put them in different place,"
So in this case, if we take a look,
maybe I want to take all
the string type values,
what we would call qualitative data,
and move that into a
separate DataFrame,
Well, the do that, you
simply use a DataFrame query
similar to what
Christopher is showing you
when we showed you how to
do querying a DataFrame,
So we say, let's do a query
using loc of a DataFrame,
and we say which rows we want,
Colon means return all rows,
which columns we want?
We simply list the
column we want returned,
and then we take that
query result and we
put it into a new DataFrame,
Presto, we now have our brand
new DataFrame containing
just the columns we needed,
So there you have it,
Python with the powers of
pandas and DataFrames,
gives us lots of clever,
simple ways to remove a
single column or to move
aside or split a DataFrame
into a new DataFrame,