>> So Christopher just
walked you through how to
actually train the model and yes,
that can feel a bit anticlimactic,
I was chatting with a data
scientist who told me that
80 percent of your
time is spent actually
preparing the data
to do the training,
and only 20 percent of your time is
actually spent training the model,
When it gets down to the code,
it's really one line of code that
you execute to train your model,
You spend most of your time
doing that preparation,
getting the data ready for training,
It's interesting, You may notice
over the next couple of modules,
same thing really is just one line of
code does all the magic for us,
It's getting the data
ready that's going to take
you most of your time,
But, we have got a model trained
based on the code that
you saw with Christopher,
So now, let's take a look at how we
actually test for model
once we trained it,
So we know it's actually
somewhat accurate and then,
we can rely on that model and make
decisions based on that model,
So how do we test a model?
When we are looking at
Christopher's content,
you saw that we had split up
our data into four parts,
We had X_train and X_test,
X_train is the data we use to train
our model along with Y_ train,
Y_train being the values
we're predicting,
X_train being our features,
Then, we also had test data,
X_test and Y_test, and that was
data we had put aside for testing,
That's what we're going to use to
check how accurate our model is,
So what we can do is take
that X_test data we put aside
and we're going to use
that to test our model,
So we use predict is
the method that we typically use
on the different models to say,
here are some values that
we would like to test with,
please try and predict values for
those different values
in our test data,
So we take the data in X_test and we
pass that in using our regressor,
which is the model object we had
created, and we call predict,
We pass in the test data
and it will pass back
a prediction for each of
the rows of test data,
We can put that into a data frame,
I'm calling it Y predicted because
that's sort of nice consistent,
We have Y_test for the actual
values for our test data,
Now, we have Y prediction
containing the predicted
values for our test data,
So now, once we're finished that,
we'll be able to compare the
results we have in Y_test,
which is the actual values that
happened for each record to
the predicted values or
model data for each of the
rows of our test data,
By comparing here, we
know the first row,
the first flight was
five minutes early,
Our model predicted it would be
just over three minutes late,
The second row, it predicted
would be 20 minutes late,
Our model predicted it would be
about six minutes late and so on,
So now, we get a sense of whether
our models are doing a good
job making those predictions,
Now, let's take a look
this in some actual code,