>> Let's take a look at a
code example of how we can
split up our data into training
data and testing data,
So just like before,
we're going to need pandas,
So let me import that in,
Let's import in a CSV file
and check out its shape,
What you're going to notice is
the fact that we have 30,000
rows and 16 columns
inside of our data,
Now we're going to keep things
a little bit simple here,
that normally at this point after
you've loaded up your CSV file,
you would probably
do some exploration,
start to get rid of some bad data,
maybe bring data in from
somewhere else, etc,
Well, we're going
the green path here,
where everything is just
going to work for us,
So we're making our lives a
little bit easier, admittedly,
But in the real world,
there would still be
a little bit of work
that you would have to do here,
So 30,000 rows, 16 columns,
Let's go ahead and start to break
down all of that information
into the appropriate spots,
So we're going to use the distance
and the elapsed time here,
So you'll notice that we
called ahead just so we
can see the first five rows here,
All of that looks nice,
and we're going to grab the delay,
and that all looks good,
So right now what we have,
is we've got two new DataFrames,
We've got x, which is our features,
This is everything
that we're going to
use to try and do our predictions,
Then over on the y side,
this is the value that we're
now trying to predict,
So given the distance
and the amount of time that
it took, how late is that?
That's what we're
trying to set up here,
Now, what we need to do in order
to be able to feed this into
a model and start to train that up is
we need some testing data
and some training data,
Where again the testing data is going
to be used to validate
all of the assumptions,
the training data is going to
be used to build up that model,
We're going to use that
nice little helper function
here of train test split,
Then we're going to set up
our x train and x test,
y train and y test,
and we're going to pass
it in the x and y,
Again, our x is going
to be our features,
our y is going to be what it is
that we're trying to predict,
We're going to set up 30 percent as
the test size and then
the random state of 42,
So now when I run this,
and I take a look at the
shape for that x train,
what we're going to notice is
21,000 rows inside of there,
When we look at the test,
what we're going to notice is
9,000 rows inside of there,
So you'll notice that we now
have 30 percent of our data that's
going to be set up as testing,
and we're going to have 70 percent of
our data that's set up as training,
Now, if you're anything like me,
and I know I am,
you might be looking at
that real quick and going,
"Hey, wait a minute, those
numbers don't seem in the lineup,
You have 30,000 rows,
shouldn't it be 20 and 10?"
Remember, we didn't say a third,
we said 30 percent,
so 30 percent of 30,000 is 9,000,
Maybe it was just me
that got caught on that,
maybe you're looking
at that and going,
"Okay, yeah, that
makes complete sense,"
Either way, there you are,
So those are a couple of numbers,
Then we'll also notice,
if I go in and grab the
head of train, for example,
that I did in fact get
back completely random
rows on the train side,
Then if I took a look at why,
I'm going to see the
exact same thing,
So there's our train and test,
again, the shape on both of those,
Then what you're going to
notice is on the head,
we're getting our random IDs,
But I do want to point
out this fact here,
that you'll notice if I do this,
I can actually go x train head,
There we go, Let's go
ahead and run this is,
and I'm going to just
draw on the screen,
make it a little easier,
Let me "Launch",
"Zoom" it real quick,
There we go, So up
the very top there,
this is my y,
and then down below, that's our x,
What I want you to notice here,
is that the IDs line up,
and that's important,
So then that way, because we've
split all of our data up,
I've got my features over here,
I've got my labels over here,
What's going to drive the prediction?
What it is that we're
trying to predict?
I've now got that in two
separate DataFrames,
We need to be able to at some
point bring all of those together,
That's what that ID column
is going to do for us,
and that's why all
of that matches up,
Okay, now that we've got
the data ready to go,
let's see how we could
begin to train up a model,