>> One of the things that
you're going to notice when you
start getting in and
playing around with data,
is the fact that you're going
to work very iteratively,
That you're going to
try a couple of things,
go back, make a couple of changes,
try it again, go back,
make a couple of changes,
try it again and so forth and so on,
The problem with doing that
with more traditional tools is
the fact that you oftentimes
have to set up a little
bit of scaffolding,
and getting to the exact spot of code
that you want to be able to run
can be a little bit clunky,
So this is where Jupyter
comes into play,
So what I want to take a look
at here is the concept of
Jupyter Notebooks and where it
is that you can set this up,
where it is that you
can run this, etc,
So Jupyter is an open source
platform or framework, if you will,
and really what it's
there to do is to give
you an integrated
development environment,
So that way, what
I'll be able to do is
maybe do a little bit of prereq work,
get to the exact spot that
I'm wanting to play with,
and just keep doing whatever it
is that I need to do in here,
Once I've got that done,
then I can move on to the next block,
and maybe I need to go back and make
a couple of changes and
then run back down,
and so forth and so on,
and that's what this is
all going to enable,
Now, you are going to notice that you
could install Jupyter
locally on your system,
That if you head on
over to jupyter,org,
you can download and install Jupyter,
get it up and running,
and actually get the
browser experience that
I'm going to be demoing for you
in just a couple of moments,
running locally on your system,
Now, I'd be remiss if
I do not highlight
the fact that Visual Studio Code also
has a wonderful integration
for Jupyter Notebooks as well,
So, if you really like to
use Visual Studio Code,
you want to stay in that environment,
then you can also configure
Visual Studio Code to give you
the ability to run your
notebooks as well,
right there inside of the editor,
which is personally one of
my favorite little things
inside of VS Code,
If you check up the
GitHub repository,
that's part of this course,
you'll see a link to how you can
go in and set all of that up,
I also want to highlight,
and this is what I'm going
to be using for my demo,
the fact that you can run
Jupyter in the Cloud,
and there's a couple of different
ways that you could do this,
In my case, I'm going
to do it by utilizing
the Azure DSVM or Data
Science Virtual Machine,
What the DSVM is,
is it's a virtual machine,
as you might expect,
that has a whole bunch of
tools already installed and
it's perfect for getting in
and playing around with data,
that most of the things
that you would need,
including Jupyter, is going to be
right there in that nice
neat little package,
All that you have to do is to say,
yes, I want this,
and then create it and
away you go from there,
Once again, we'll have the
instructions on how you could set that
up inside of the GitHub repository,
Let's check out how we can use
Jupyter to start playing
around with some code,
So what you've got here is
the Jupyter Hub set
up inside of my DSVM,
my Data Science Virtual Machine,
and I've already got a few different
folders and things like that,
that come just pre-built
inside of there,
But what I want to do is play
around with a brand new one and
start creating some
notebooks inside of there,
So what I did is I hit New right
up there on the top right,
and what you're going
to notice is I've got
the option to hit folder,
So I'm going to create
a brand new folder here
and you'll notice that it
will just automatically
give me this new little folder
right here called untitled folder,
In order to rename that,
it's an additional
step here that I need
to hit the little check
and then come up here,
hit Rename, and now I can give it
my very creative name of demo,
So now I hit Rename,
now you're going to notice
that it's set up as demo,
Now, I can click on that link,
and now I can start creating
different items that I
might want inside of here,
Now, what's worth highlighting
the fact that inside of here,
I can have things like CSV files,
images and anything else
that I might be using as
part of the manipulations and
work that I'm going to be doing,
But the real center to
everything that we're going to
be working with is a notebook,
So you'll notice once
again that I hit New,
and then there's a whole bunch of
pre-configured options for
me for different notebooks,
What I really like about this
is that if you want to use,
say for example R,
that I've got that
option right there,
if you're wanting to
play around with Scala,
you can do that,
Both R and Scala, by the way,
are languages that are very popular
when you're working with data,
Or I can also go in and choose
my different Python
notebooks as well,
So what I'm going to do is I'm
going to hit py 37 default,
and that's going to set up a
brand new notebook for me,
that is just simply Python,
Now, in order to make this function,
there's always going to be a kernel,
You might have noticed right up here,
there's a little thing that
was going on right up here,
where it's telling me
that it was creating
a kernel and setting all of that up,
that's my runtime behind the scenes,
So if you want to go
in and play around
with that little runtime
that's making it all happen,
then you can hit the Kernel Window,
and then you can choose
to say restarted,
you can reconnect in case
something maybe has
gone wrong or maybe
you opened this up
from somewhere else,
you can restart and have it rerun
everything inside of your notebook,
Then last but not least,
you'll notice right
here that you have
the ability to restart
and clear output,
One big thing to note
about the notebooks when
you're playing with them,
and let's say I may
be load up some data
and I manipulate it
and I get a result,
that actually becomes
part of your notebook,
So you can refer back to
this with the answers,
if you will, already in place,
If you want to start all over again,
that's where that clear
output comes into play,
So that way, it will just get rid of
everything and allow you to redo
whatever it was that
you were working on,
Now, I also want to highlight in
here one very important spot,
and that is that little
square bracket placeholder,
if you will, that's right there,
That will indicate one of
three different things,
If it's blank like it is now,
what that's going to indicate
is that whatever is in
that cell has not run,
Now, if it is running,
then what will happen instead,
is there will be an
asterisk inside of there,
and it's hard for me to get it a
real big asterisk using the tool,
So you can see it's there,
If you see an asterisk,
what that means is that it's
executing, it's currently running,
The last thing that you'll
notice is a number in there,
and what that number is going
to indicate is the order
in which that cell has executed,
and that becomes important because
even though the cells are
going to go top to bottom,
the order of execution doesn't
necessarily need to be top to bottom,
That can actually help
you out sometimes,
Let's say I'm all the way
down towards the bottom,
I've got a ladder work that's
been going on up here,
I try to execute this
one little line of code,
and then I forgot to do something,
Maybe I forgot to load up a library
or to run one last
little line of code,
Well, then what I can do is just
create another cell down
at the very bottom,
run that one little line that I need,
and then go back up,
and then rerun that cell,
So it gives you a lot
of flexibility there,
But you just have to
be careful to make
sure that things are executing
in the order in which you
expect them to execute,
So let's play around
just a little bit here,
I'm going go ahead and say
name equals Christopher,
and then I'm going to say
print name, just like that,
Now, I can run my cell,
There are buttons to run the cells,
You can go in and explore
the buttons on your own,
I'm going be honest with you,
I never remember what
the buttons are,
because there's really
just two shortcut keys
that you need to know,
"Ctrl" "Enter" and "Shift" "Enter",
Watch the difference,
What I'm going to do
here is I'm going to hit
"Ctrl" "Enter" and what
"Ctrl" "Enter" will do is it will
run that cell, and that's it,
It'll just run that cell,
stay there and we're done,
Contrast that with "Shift" "Enter",
So now, I'm going to
hit "Shift" "Enter",
Now, what I want you to notice
is it's still ran the cell,
you'll notice the number
changed from a one to two,
but now I get a brand new cell,
When I use "Shift" "Enter",
what's going to happen
is it will run the cell,
move to the next,
and if there's not already one there,
then it will create a brand new one,
What are the really cool thing
about Jupyter Notebooks?
Is the fact that if I just want to
see what's inside of a variable,
then what I can do is just
end my block with it,
run it, and then it will just
display whatever is inside of there,
What's really cool about
that is the fact that
you'll be doing all really cool
things inside of your notebook,
and then I just want to see
what's inside of an item,
just end your code
with it and it will
print out whatever
is inside of there,
It's probably my favorite feature
inside of Jupyter Notebooks,
because quite frequently,
you're going to be
working with different
pieces of data,
you're not going to necessarily
know what's going on,
You just want a real quick sneak
preview of what's going on,
Jupyter is there to help you out,
The last little thing that
I want to mention is I can
also change my cell
type to be Markdown,
Now, I can use Markdown
inside of here,
So this is, if I can
spell world, there we go,
this is a great way to leave myself,
apparently I'm not able to talk
and type at the same time today,
but that's all right, some
notes, just like that,
So that way I want to indicate
anything else that might be
going on inside up here,
then I can just do
that with Markdown,
Now, Markdown does behave
like a normal cell,
So you'll notice that it's an
edit mode here at the moment,
but when I do a "Ctrl" "Enter"
just to run that cell,
now you'll notice that it
will put it into a more
proper display here,
So maybe what I could do is
I could move that cell up,
I'm just hitting those little
arrows right up there,
up to the very top,
So now I've got that as
part of my hello world,
So there is the quick version,
if you will, of
getting in and working
around with Jupyter Notebooks,
There's an awful lot of power
and tooling inside of there,
but that's probably
the most common tools,
the most common
options that you'll be
using when you get
in and play around,
This is going to be the core of
all the demos that we're going
to be doing in this course,
Everything that we're
going to do is going to be
done inside of our Jupyter Notebooks,
I again want to highlight
the fact that you
can run this in the Cloud
like I am with DSVM,
you can run this locally,
and you could also do this
inside Visual Studio Code,
Again, you can check out
the GitHub repository
for links on how to do
all the installations and how
to set up Visual Studio Code,