>> So in the last model when
we're doing calculations,
we explored very briefly
a library called NumPy,
Now NumPy, if you've actually started
exploring any data
science courses already,
you may have actually
already encountered NumPy,
You'll see a lot of modules
talking about using the NumPy
objects and things like that,
because NumPy is actually a library
that's used not just for
calculations in general,
but it's also designed for
doing matrix calculations,
So because it can do
matrix calculations,
it needs a way of storing matrices,
so it has an ability to store things
like arrays and such as well,
Now, why am I saying all this?
Well, because it turns out
if we take a closer look at
the values that we predicted when we
trained or when we tested
specifically our model,
you might notice
something interesting,
So when we called predict
for our model and
passed in the test aid and asked it
to predicate some predicted values,
If you actually look at
the type of y prediction,
you might have noticed something,
which is that y prediction,
if you look at the datatype,
is actually a NumPy array,
So it's not actually a DataFrame,
whereas y_test is a DataFrame,
Now this is significant because
so far we've been working
with Pandas DataFrames,
So when we were doing queries,
we learned how to query
a Pandas DataFrame,
When we were looking at information,
like how do I display
the first few rows
or the last 10 rows and so on,
we were doing all these with
methods on Pandas DataFrames,
So it's even possible maybe when
you are trying some
of this out yourself,
that you did something like, "Hey,
let's do a y_pred duck tail to look
at the last five rows," and it
failed because that method
doesn't exist on NumPy arrays,
That's a method that only
exist on a DataFrame,
So the other thing that might
happen is you might be
doing things like trying
to merge two DataFrames together
or split two DataFrames apart,
and you try and do again
those actions on this
y_pred and it'll all
fail because again,
it's not a DataFrame,
it's a NumPy array,
So let's just talk a little bit
more about NumPy and
explore that some more,
So it's a Python package for
scientific computing used for
a lot of matrix calculations,
It has an assortment of classes
and methods that will help you out,
When you're doing Python
for data science,
you'll end up working with
a mix of pandas objects and
methods as well as NumPy
objects and methods,
In NumPy, you have an array,
So in pandas, we had a series that's
very similar to a
one-dimensional NumPy array,
In fact, if I wanted to clear it,
if you would compare the
code for a numpy array on
the left and a panda
series on the other side,
you'll see the code
is almost identical,
Here, I can tell it's an array
because I declared
it as a NumPy array,
here I declared as a panda series,
but the syntax is the same,
If I want to print all the values in
the series or a specific
value in the series,
the syntax is again still the same,
The big difference is you
have an implicit index with
NumPy arrays and you have an
explicit index if it's displayed 0,
1, 2 when you have a pandas series,
and they have different
functionality,
A two-dimensional NumPy array is very
similar to a Pandas DataFrame
in terms its structure,
When you're writing
the code to access it,
and to create it, again it's
going to look very similar,
I declare a NumPy array and I
specify the values for
each row and each column,
If I want to print all the values,
I just pass in the array name,
if I want a particular row
or a particular value,
I specify the index column position
and the index row position;
row then column in that order,
Then if I've used
the DataFrame again,
pass in the values for
the different columns
and the different rows,
print the entire DataFrame,
or you can use that
iloc index location to
specify a row and column position
to request a specific value,
So again, at first glance,
they seem to be almost identical,
but they are different classes
and they have different capabilities,
So one of the things
you're going to run
into is there's going to be
times where you may want the
functionality of the DataFrame,
but it's in a NumPy array,
or maybe you want
the functionality of
a NumPy array and
it's in a DataFrame,
or you're trying to merge data
from two objects together,
one is a NumPy array,
one's a dataframe, and when
you try to merge them,
you'll get errors saying
they're different data types,
So you might need to move data
between a numpy and pandas object,
I'll give you one example here,
In this case, if I wanted
my predicted values
to be in a Pandas DataFrame
instead of a NumPy array,
all I have to do is call
the DataFrame constructor,
pass in the NumPy array,
that's an object it will accept,
and it will return to me a dataframe
containing the same values,
Now you can see that y_pred
is still a NumPy array,
but my y_pred DataFrame
is actually a DataFrame,
So as you explore that
world data science,
be prepared, this is
going to happen to you,
You will have times
when something's in
a NumPy object and you need it
in a Pandas object or something's in
a Pandas object and you
needed a NumPy object,
I'm not going to cover every possible
conversion that might exist,
but be prepared for it
and there's lots of
great documentation out to help
you when you're looking
at a specific scenario,
Now let's take a look at
this in the actual code,