>> So we've trained our model
and we've tested our model,
We passed in the data in x test
to predict a set of values,
which is now stored in y predict,
and then we've compared those
values to what we had in y test,
which were the actual
values for our test data,
But so far we were just
comparing those row by row,
That's very hard when you
try to get a sense of
the overall accuracy of your model,
So what we want to be able to
do is do some calculations
to return to us a sense of
overall accuracy of the model,
So if we take a look
at the code here,
I'm importing a new library
called Scikit-learn, which
we're going to be using here,
So we're going to
start by just training
and testing our model again,
This is exact same code we've
done in the previous lessons,
So don't worry about that code,
You'll see it's exactly the
same code you run before,
still doing linear regression,
training our model, and then passing
in some test data to get
some predicted results,
So what we're going to
do differently now,
is we'll use some calculations
to determine the accuracy,
One of the many different
ways to measure
accuracy is to look at
the Mean Squared Error,
This is calculated
by doing the mean of
actuals minus predicted
values squared,
You could write a Loop
that would do that
using Straight Python Code,
You've learned how to do
that with the learning,
had to do Loop Logic when you're in
the introduction to programming
courses with the Python,
But, if you actually go to
the Scikit-learn library,
you'll discover it contains a
number of different methods to
help you calculate metrics which
are great for evaluating your model,
Most of them are designed for this,
So what I can simply do,
is I can say, "Hey,
let's import from scikit-learn
the metrics and just
calculate Mean Squared Error,
pass it the actual results
for your test data,
the predicted results
and it returns the
mean squared error,"
Just as a general guideline
for this particular metric,
a lower value is good,
Another common metric you
might measure as the
Root Mean Squared Error,
which is literally the square
root of Mean Squared Error,
But scikit-learn doesn't
have a method for this,
That's okay though because there's
another library we
can use called NumPy,
NumPy has a number of
different functions you can use
for mathematical calculations,
including one which
calculates square root,
So if we just calculate the square
root of the Mean Squared Error,
then we get Root Mean Squared Error,
So NumPy is another useful library
that we use when we're trying to
get these calculations
to measure our averages
and our totals to get a
sense of overall accuracy,
I'll just throw out a couple
of other examples here,
Different types of
models are going to have
different metrics that we
look at to measure accuracy,
So when you look at
data science courses,
depending on the type of
model you're learning,
you're going to see
different metrics,
But the key here being
Scikit-learn and
NumPy will often have the
methods to help you do it,
So just a couple of
other examples here,
we've got the Mean Absolute Error,
It's the mean of
the absolute value of the
actuals minus predicted values,
The difference being it's a
little less sensitive if you
have some odd data
in the middle of it,
what we call outliers,
Lower numbers are better,
Another common one is the R-squared,
In this one, generally speaking,
the higher your R-squared,
the better the model,
So I'm not going to get
into what all these numbers
mean and represent,
But the key takeaway
here is when you're
training model to
measure the accuracy,
different models will
have different metrics,
Scikit-learn and NumPy are
going to help you out a lot,