>> Let's see how we
can set up our model,
So what we're going to do
as previously mentioned,
is we're going to bring in
our pandas library and bring
up our train test split,
We're going to do exactly
what we did before,
So I'm not going to
spend a lot of time
walking back through this code,
but this is what we've seen,
that we've seen how
to read in the CSV,
We've seen how to drop our values
that are null or otherwise,
We're going to then go grab
our distance and elapsed time,
We're going to grab our arrival delay
and we're going to
split all of that up,
So basically everything
that we've seen,
all of those individual demos,
all fall right there,
It all comes together,
So let's go ahead and
run that little bit,
Boom, Now, we're ready
to set up our model,
Now here's what I want you to notice,
we're going to go grab our
LinearRegression from sklearn,
We're then going to
set up an instance of
that class and then we're going
to go ahead and call it fit,
We're going to pass in
our training data and for
our features and for our labels,
So again, X is going to be
what's going to drive the value,
y is going to be the value
that we're going to drop,
Now I'm openly going
to admit here that
the ending is a little bit
anticlimactic because we've
now set up this model,
but we don't know anything about it,
We haven't seen yet maybe how
we could predict a value,
You'll also notice that we haven't
yet used any of that testing data,
Well, the reason that we haven't used
any of the testing data is all the
we've done at this point is
we've just done our training,
All that we've done is
we've set up our model,
Now, it's time to turn our attention
to see how well did we do?
That's where we're going to
look at in the next module,