>> So when you wrapped
up with Christopher,
you would have successfully
loaded some data,
split it into training and test data,
and even trained a model,
So now, the next step
was basically to see if
the model could make
predictions and if so,
how accurate are those predictions?
So you know, if you
can trust the results
coming from your trained
model and if it's
going to make sense to
make business decisions
or to make changes based
on the predictions,
Can you trust the
prediction from the model?
So we need to be able to test
our model and get a sense of how
accurate the predictions are,
So what we're going
to need first though,
is to rerun some of our
code we saw earlier,
So I'm just going to import
all the same libraries you were
using in the cobe with
Christopher when you
are training your model and I'm just
going to rerun the same
code that you were
looking at that was going ahead
and said loading our dataset,
still working with
the flight dataset,
getting rid of the
rows with null values,
splitting up our
features and our labels,
the values we're using to train
the model and the
value we're trying to
predict and then splitting that
into training and test data,
So that's all code you've seen before
and you finished with that
one little line of code,
It's crazy, you put all this work
and think data science can be so
complicated to train a model and you
discover training a model
is all of one line of code,
It's preparing the data that
really takes up most of your time,
Now that we have trained
the model by calling fit,
We have a trained model we call
the predict method to
actually make predictions,
Now, if we're going
to predict values,
we need to be able to predict values
if we want to check accuracy,
We'd like to make some predictions
for values where we actually
know what the actual outputs were,
That's why you put
aside that test data,
because we have a whole
bunch of rows inside
X test for which we actually
know what happened,
We know how many minutes
late those flights were,
that's the values we
stored in Y test,
So if we pass the values in X test,
which are all bunch of flights,
where we know what happened
and we say to the model, "Hey,
predict what the flight delay will
be for each of these records,"
Then we can compare the predicted
values to the actual values,
So that's exactly what
we're going to do,
So if we look at our code though,
it's really only one line,
We're going to call regressor,
which if you remember up here,
that was what we called our
linear regression object,
which we just trained,
Now we can ask that trained model to
predict values for each row in
X test and we're
going to put those in
a dataframe called Y predict,
So we're going to put
that into Y predict
and now it's done and you can print
those values out and you can see
all the different values
it's predicted for each row,
Then you can compare those
values to the actual values
we had put a side for each of
those toast rows when we did
our splitting ever data,
You can see that for the
first row, the actual delay,
it was five minutes
early that first flight,
whereas our model predicted it
would be about three minutes late,
The second row, the actual
flight was 12 minutes early,
and our model predicted was going
to be about six minutes late,
Third row predicted it would be
four minutes late when
the actual value was
about nine minutes early,
So I can see that my models
maybe not quite perfect
yet and this is where you
need to go look into this data
science courses and you would learn
techniques to go back and
see how you get better
accuracy on your model,
But we're focusing on the code
part here and you can see
here we have that ability
to take our test data,
pass it to the model,
and get back predicted values,
What I'll take a look at
in the next module is
some mathematical
calculations you can do to
get a better sense of
accuracy because reading
through all those rows manually
could be a little clunky,