>> Before we get into this module,
I want to make sure that I'm
setting expectations appropriately,
We are not going to get
into selecting which model,
differences between the model, etc,
There's a lot to that,
We actually do have content
that you can go check out,
that will give you more
information about that,
I've mentioned to a handful of times
already, the GitHub repository,
Again, if you go there,
you're going to notice
that we have links to
additional resources where you can
start to dig deeper into
those types of conversations,
Like, hey, what's the
difference between
logical regression and
linear regression?
So you can go check all of that out,
The example that I want to walk
through here is going to
use linear regression,
which is designed to predict
a value and potentially show
all of us that on a
neat little chart,
That's what linear
regression is all about,
Again, well, what you want to
be able to do is to predict how
late or how early a particular
flight is going to be,
That's exactly what linear
regression can do for us,
Again, if you want a deeper
conversation on all of that,
you can check out the links
inside the repository
and learn more about all
the possibilities there,
Let's go ahead and take a look at
how we're going to take all of
our prepared data and start
to feed that into a model,
So if you remember from before,
this is what we've got,
We've got our training data,
We've got our testing data,
We've got our features,
We've got our labels,
We're ready to go,
We're all dressed up, now
we just need a destination,
You need to have somewhere to go,
That somewhere that
we're going to go,
is going to be into
some form of a model,
into some form of an algorithm,
and in this particular case,
it's going to be linear regression,
So linear regression is going
to give us that ability
to predict a value there,
that's going to be
some form of a line,
thus the name linear regression,
See, it's not just a clever name,
Now there's a little fit function or
a little fit method
that we're going to
use after we get a
bit all of our data,
that's going to actually give
us the ability in turn
to start to predict
values and give us outcomes for
any new data that we fill into it,
As I mentioned at the outset,
there's a lot of different
ways that we can do this,
There's a lot of different classes
that are available to us and
we can use Scikit-learn and there's
other utilities out there that
you might want to check out,
We're going to use Scikit-learn
to perform this operation,
So it typically is going to
follow the same pattern here,
where we're going to import
in the desired class that's
going to do our work,
We're going to create
an instance of that,
and then we're going
to call fit to have
it start doing all of its work,
Now, that's what I'm
about to demo here,
But as you might expect,
there's still more to it,
So when I go in and
I run all of this,
the next question becomes,
well, how accurate is that?
That's what we're going
to see in a later module,
For right now, what I want to
focus in on is the mechanic,
How do we now take our data
and fit that into a model?
That's going to be our core demo