>> So we've seen how after
we've trained a model,
we can compare our test
to our predicted data,
But the first time we did it,
when we looked at it, we
just saw a list of values,
and it's not really practical
to visually look at
all the results from our
actual test data results,
the actual values predicted
versus the values
predicted by our model,
and compare them row by row by row,
Visually, it's just not a
practical way to look at things,
So what we'll typically do is,
we take advantage of the
fact that we're programmers,
and we use some code to do
calculations to get a sense of
the overall accuracy of how
effective our model is
in making predictions,
But it still comes down to comparing
the predicted values
and the actual values,
But the difference is,
what we want to do is use
some calculations to compare the two,
One of the most common methods we
use is something called
Mean Squared Error,
So the Mean Squared Error,
if you actually look
at the formula for it,
is just the mean of
the actual values,
minus the predicted values squared,
Now, I could write some
Python code, in fact,
you learned enough in the
introduction to Python course to
write a loop that would go
through all the actual values,
go through all the predicted values,
subtract one from the other,
calculate the value squared,
and perform this calculation,
You could do that,
but there's a better way,
Luckily, there's a whole
bunch of great libraries
out there that will help you
when you're doing data science,
The scikit-learn library,
has all sorts of
great functions for
scientific calculations,
including one called
Mean Squared Error,
So all I really have to do is
import the scikit-learn library,
in particular, when you're doing
these types of calculations,
you'll probably want the metrics,
and then I just say calculate
the Mean Squared Error of
my actual results versus
my predictive results,
and now I can get a sense of my
total accuracy of the model,
Generally speaking, just from
a data science perspective,
a lower value is going to be better,
Lower error is good,
Now, sometimes there's a whole bunch
of different numbers and
metrics you can look at,
another one is the Root
Mean of Squared Error,
which is just the square root of
Mean Squared Error, which
we just calculated,
But scikit-learn doesn't have a
method we can use to calculate it,
So there's another library
you're going to start
exploring with and playing
with when you do data science
as well, which is NumPy,
So what NumPy will do
is NumPy has all sorts
of functions designed for
straight math calculations,
and including one which
calculates the square root,
So if I have the Mean Squared
Error method in scikit-learn,
and I have the ability to
calculate square root with NumPy,
then I can put those together to
get my Root Mean Squared Error,
So these are the two libraries
that are really going to
help you when you're looking to
evaluate the accuracy of your model,
Different types of
models you're going to
learn as you explore data science,
are going to have
different metrics that you
evaluate to check the accuracy,
But generally speaking, between
NumPy and scikit-learn,
you should always
have some method out
there that's going to help you
perform those calculations,
So NumPy for the basic
mathematical calculations,
and scikit-learn often has a lot of
specific methods for predicting
and measuring accuracy
of your models,
So now let's go take a look
at that in some actual code,