>> Christopher just took
you through some of
the things we can do
with Jupyter Notebooks,
Now, one of the challenges you're
going to work with when
you start playing with
Jupyter notebooks is
yet some other tools
you might need to work with as well,
specifically Anaconda and Conda,
Anaconda is an open
source distribution
of Python and R often
used for data science,
When you install Anaconda,
it comes with about 1500 different
packages that you can use,
It has this graphical interface
called Anaconda Navigator,
It also has a command
line interface called
Anaconda Prompt and it also
comes with a tool called Conda,
So Conda is a tool that you can
use to create a managed
Python environments,
Now back in the original
introduction to Python series,
we talked about how we could use
virtual environments to manage
all the different packages we
work with when we're coding
in Python and the different
versions of Python,
So that becomes important
with notebooks as well,
But we tend to use Conda
when we need to manage
packages and environments
for Jupyter Notebooks,
So what you're going to
want to do is install
Anaconda and then after
you've installed Anaconda,
you just launch the Anaconda prompt
and then to create a virtual
environment using Conda,
you use the Conda create command,
you give your environment
a name and you
specify the version of Python,
you're going to be running,
The dash y there is
simply a way of saying,
if you ask me questions to
confirm is this running,
just answer yes to the
questions by default,
just so you understand what
that little dash y is doing,
So you just have to come up
with a name for the Notebook
and know which version of
Python you want to work with,
Once you created the environment,
then you can activate it,
So you simply tell Conda,
tell it to activate your Notebook,
A couple of other useful commands you
might need down the
road if you need to
deactivate your environment
to move back and forth,
you have Conda deactivate and if
you no longer need an environment,
you can delete it by
using the Conda remove
command once you have
activated an environment,
So you create an environment,
you activate an environment,
then you can install the libraries
you're going to use
inside that environment,
So we can install pandas,
you might be installing things
like Matplotlib, NumPy,
These are some of the libraries
you're going to start getting to
know if you start exploring
that world of data science,
so you may need to install them,
Otherwise what will happen is when
you are running Jupyter Notebooks,
you're going to see error
messages coming back saying,
I don't know what Matplotlib is,
so this is how we're going
to fix that problem,
After you've installed the libraries
that you need to use for your code
you're also going to install Jupyter
itself for the Jupyter Notebooks,
If at any point you lose
track of which libraries
you've already installed,
you can always use Conda list to get
a list of all the
installed libraries,
Once you've installed but you need,
you can simply launch Jupyter
Notebooks from inside
the active environment and
now your code should be
able to access all the libraries
you need to do your coding,
Couple of little tips
that might be useful,
I've run into this before,
when you're back in
the command line
environment and you've
launched Jupyter Notebooks
and you want to go back,
maybe installed an extra package,
Control C will take you back to
the Anaconda Prompt and
sometimes after you've
installed a package,
I find it doesn't seem to
recognize it right away
when I launch the Jupyter
Notebook, and that happens to me,
I usually find if I deactivate
the environment and
activate it again,
it usually works,
doesn't happen often,
but it's something you can try
if you run into that issue,
All right, let's try it,