>> Well, if you made it this far,
then I guess the last
thing that we have to
say at this point is thank you,
We also want to encourage you to get
in and really start playing
with all the different tips,
tricks, and tools that
we've demoed here,
>> You got some of those
Python skills ready,
now is perfect time to go look
for some data science tutorials,
check out some of the stuff
on Microsoft Learn at
docs,Microsoft,com, some
of the quick starts,
You can find some
really great tutorials
to get started with machine learning,
training models, and it should be a
little easier now because you
already know some of the code,
>> So if you're looking for
specific spots to go
in and start looking,
check out the GitHub repository
that we've linked to,
You're going to notice that
we curated a handful of
nice next steps and how you can
continue growing from there,
So now's the perfect time,
start writing some
code, Thanks again,
>> Thanks again, See you next time,