>> So we just talked a bit about how
to create virtual environments
and why they're important,
Let's take a look at that
in some actual code,
So I have here a Jupyter Notebook,
One of the things we
often do in working with
Python is to import different
libraries; Pandas, NumPy,
You'll see some of these as
we go through this course,
Now, in this case,
I have one where I'm importing
something from matplotlib,
This is another library we're
going to play around with later,
When I run this line of code
and try to import the library,
I get an error message saying,
"Cannot find the module matplotlib,"
This is probably the number
1 error message you're
going to get used to seeing when
you're working inside
Jupyter Notebooks,
So we want to learn how do we
deal with that message
when it comes up,
When we did the intro to Python
course with Christopher,
we learned how to work
with virtual environments,
But with Jupyter Notebooks,
we usually do this with
something called conda,
So if I close this
down, you can see here,
this was actually the conda
environment I was using,
but we aren't going to be using
that one because it was
giving us an error message,
So if we have launched
the Anaconda Prompt,
you can see right now I'm
in the base environment,
because of the word
base appearing here,
So what I'm going to need to do,
is create a new virtual environment,
So I could tell conda, I want
to create a new environment,
and I'm going to give it the
name Python environment,
It's going to be a Python
environment with Python version 3,7,
I'm just putting a dash y here,
so if any prompts come
up asking me questions,
it will simply automatically
answer yes to those
types of questions,
Now, it's going off and creating
this virtual environment
for me, for conda,
Once I've created that environment,
I can then move to that environment
by saying, "Conda activate,"
It's even nice, it
gives me a little hint
here in case I forget the commands,
Activate my environment,
which I called PythonEnv,
Remember, this is just the name
I gave to the environment,
Once you've activated
that environment,
you'll even notice that the prompt
will actually show you
the environment name,
So you can remember that you're
in your virtual environment,
Now, I can install any of
the libraries I might need to
use when I'm writing my code,
So in our case, we are getting
an error, trying matplotlib,
So we can say, "Hey, conda,
would you please install
matplotlib for me?"
So now, it's going to
install that library,
So but I'll be able to access
it from inside of my code,
Now, once we've installed
the matplotlib library,
you might have other
libraries you'll need to
install as well depending on
what you're trying to do,
But there's one extra library you
always want to install and that one,
so maybe you install Pandas,
maybe install NumPy, but
we definitely want to
install one called, Jupyter,
So we actually want
to install Jupyter,
which is what runs the Notebooks
inside our virtual environment,
Because that way when we
run the Jupyter Notebooks,
we know the Jupyter
installation is actually
using the libraries that we have
installed inside this
virtual environment,
Once the Notebooks
had been installed,
then we'll actually going to launch
Jupyter Notebooks from the
actual Anaconda Prompt itself,
So this time when I say
run Jupyter Notebook,
I'm launching Jupyter
Notebooks from inside
my conda environment, PythonEnv,
This time when we navigate to
our Notebook and we go to
that line of code where it
couldn't find matplotlib,
we're going to see that line of
code is going to run successfully,
So you get a little peek
behind the scenes here
at all the various notebooks,
Susan has created for this course,
But if I go back to the one where
we had imported matplotlib,
you'll see here before we
was giving us an error,
But now when we run that line
of code, it runs successfully,
So no more errors,
So now, when you're using
a Jupyter Notebook and you get
that error message saying,
"Hey, I can't find that library,"
You know how to create
a conda environment,
install your libraries there,
run your Jupyter Notebook,
and get it going successfully,