>> As is mentioned on the outset,
what we're going to
focus in on is some of
the common libraries and
tooling that you're going to
use when it comes to working
down the path of data science,
So along those lines,
we're going to take a look at are
really common library
known as pandas,
Now sorry to disappoint
right upfront,
so this has nothing
to do with the bears,
I know I was disappointed
when I first found that out,
But rather it's a library
that has a couple of
very common utilities that you'll
be using to help work with,
manage, and manipulate the data
as you start to analyze it,
So what is pandas?
Pandas is an open source
BSD-license library,
and it's really geared towards
high performance and
familiar data structures,
that what you're going
to notice in here
is that we're going to
have a serious library
that's going to be a
little bit like a list
only gives us a couple of
additional tools as well,
We're also going to see a
DataFrame where if you've played
around with Excel or maybe
a relational database,
that you'll feel very comfortable
inside of a DataFrame,
So first up, what is series?
Well, Series is very
similar to a Python list,
that what it's going to be is
a single dimensional array of
objects where I have all of
my values sitting there,
and they'll have some
form of an index,
One big difference however,
between a Series and a
List is the fact that we
can set our index to really be
whatever it is that we might want,
By default, it's going
to be zero based,
but if you do need some
level of control over that,
you can have that as opposed to
an index which is always
going to be in zero based,
Now to create a brand new series,
what you're going to do
is use the constructor,
So if you've already played
around with classes before,
you'll know that you
go ahead and call
this just like you
would a normal method,
and then pass in the
appropriate items,
You'll notice that when
you get right down to it,
what we're doing here is
we're really actually just
converting in a list into a series,
So you'll notice the
square brackets here,
that's what we're using to
indicate a list typically,
So we're actually converting
this into a series,
The other thing that I
want to highlight here,
is you'll notice this
little pd right here,
You might be wondering, "Okay,
Well, what is pd?"
Commonly, when you import
in the pandas library,
you'll rename this as pd,
pd being short for pandas,
If you've seen me do other videos,
you may know the fact that I
really don't like single, and two,
and three letter variable
names or otherwise,
that to me it's not necessarily
as clear as to what it might be,
That being said, I will
always go with convention,
So convention always override
my own personal opinion because well,
I have opinions on everything,
But the community has
decided that when we use
pandas that we'll go ahead
and abbreviate this as pd,
So I follow right along with that,
and I do recommend
that you do the same,
that whenever there's a convention,
you should go ahead and fall in
line there because after all,
it's not just going to be you that
we'll be looking at your code,
but it's frequently going to be
other Python developers as well,
and you want to make sure
that they know what it
is that you've been up
to inside of your code,
So while I'm not necessarily
a fan of one and two letter
variable and namespace names,
I'll still go ahead
and use pd because
again, that's the convention,
So you'll notice here we can
go ahead and set all this up,
When we go ahead and display this,
it will then show up as
just simply that little list
right there with the index,
and you're also going
to notice that if I
want to go access a particular item,
I can use the normal index functions,
So here is my airports
with two just like that,
I can do a for loop to loop
through each one of those,
So if I print all of those out,
you'll notice that I'll
get Seattle-Tacoma,
Dulles, London
Heathrow, and Schiphol,
down at the very bottom,
Okay, Let's turn our
attention now to DataFrames,
I would say that this is probably
the most common datatype that you'll
be using when you're getting in and
playing around inside of
anything that's data science,
A DataFrame is a two
dimensional data structure,
If you've played around
inside of a database,
if you've played around
inside of a spreadsheet,
you're going to feel
very much at home here,
Because what you're going
to notice is that we have
columns and we have our rows,
and our columns are
going to have names,
So you'll notice that
we've got name here,
we've got city here,
we've got country, all
the way on the end there,
We've got our normal columns,
just like we would expect,
You're also going to notice again
similar or more to a database then
maybe to a spreadsheet
that we'll also have
a column that will be our index,
and you'll also notice
that you'll have
the ability to control that,
by default it's going
to be zero-based,
But if maybe I'm importing
in from somewhere else,
maybe from a table,
maybe from a CSV file,
maybe there is already
IDs that have been set,
that I could go in and identify, hey,
this is the column that
I want you to use as
an index rather than doing
the zero-based there,
So you do get the
ability to control that,
If you want to create a DataFrame,
what you're going to notice is that
we'll use again a constructor,
but effectively we're
going to convert
a list of lists into our DataFrame,
So I want to highlight
just this item right here,
where you'll notice that
we've got Seattle-Tacoma,
which is the name of the airport,
You'll notice that we've got
the city, which is Seattle,
and then we've got the
country, which is USA,
Then you'll notice the
next list down below that,
I'll highlight that one in blue here,
You'll notice on that one
that we've got Dulles,
we've got Washington, and USA,
So again, we've got the
name of the airport,
the city, and the country,
So each one of those
is an individual list,
We're going to take
all of those together,
convert that into a DataFrame,
and the result is
going to wind up being
that little table that
you're seeing right there,
So you'll notice that Seattle-Tacoma,
Dulles, London Heathrow, Schiphol,
and Changi, all become our
individual airport names,
Just imagine if you are the
Changi was added onto there,
even though it just wasn't
listed in the code above,
You'll notice the cities,
and then you'll also
notice the countries,
So what happened is
we took those lists
and we converted that
into a table structure,
But what I want you to notice
is the column names there,
The column names are quite frankly,
not overly helpful that I got
column names of zero, one, and two,
Zero, one, and two
don't tell me anything,
Not only that, but
dealing with data where
everything depends on position
can get really tricky,
because you have to be
really careful about
things moving around and so forth,
So whenever we can identify
something based on name,
that's typically going to be
the way that we want to do it,
So rather than going with those
numbers that we see by default,
let's instead identify what
our column names should be,
So you'll notice the
last parameter there,
which is our columns,
So now when we run this bit of code,
now we'll actually wind
up with the column names,
So you'll notice that we've got name,
we've got city, and
we've got country,
You're going to notice that
there is a lot of tools
that are available to us
inside of the DataFrame,
and we're going to
take a look at those
in the next couple of videos,
But for now, this is how we
go in and create the items,
Let's get in and take a look at a
couple of real quick code demos,
so we can see this in action,