>> When you're working with data,
you're typically going to be
importing this in from a database,
from a CSV file, from somewhere else,
When you're pulling that data in,
the first thing you'll
typically want to
do is figure out what
it is that you have,
because real-world data is messy,
There's going to be errors,
there's going to be inconsistencies,
there's going to be
missing values, etc,
that before you begin performing
any operations on the data,
you first need to figure out
what in the world you've got,
So fortunately, what we're
going to notice with the
DataFrame is that we
have a lot of different ways
that we can explore our data,
Now, like we did in the prior module,
we are going to hard-code in what
our DataFrame is going to be,
Just to make things
a little bit easier,
Don't worry, However, we
are going to show off
the code to actually
load this up from a CSV,
So how can we go in and explore this?
Again, there's a whole host of
different ways that we can do this,
A couple of the most
common are head and tail,
Where with head, we can
indicate the number of
rows from the top that we
want to be able to see,
and with tail, as you might expect,
we can see the number of rows from
the bottom that we want
to be able to see,
So head 3 is going to give us
the first three rows, tail 3,
of course, is going to give
us the last three rows,
We can also find out
what the shape is,
or basically, what
are the dimensions,
Or in other words,
it will give us the number of
rows and the number of columns,
So if we take a look
at the output here,
what we're going to notice is
seven for the number of rows,
and then three for the
number of columns,
Now, you might be thinking,
"Well, wait a minute, Christopher,
I'm counting four columns
because I see index,
and I see name, city, and country,"
You're right, What the three
is actually indicating to us,
because there will
always be an index,
is the number of data
columns that we have,
So three is the number
of data columns,
seven is going to be
the number of rows,
zero through six, of course,
that's going to be seven,
so that's the shape that
we're getting back,
But shape is really
a high level beck,
It's nice to know what it
is that we're dealing with,
but sometimes we need
a little bit lower level
of information here,
and this is where
info comes into play,
With info, we can get an
awful lot of what's going
on inside of our data,
So what we're going to
see when we run info
is the number of rows or entries,
We're going to see the index range,
so 0-6 in our case here,
we're going to see the
number of columns,
we're going to see the information
about each column
including the names,
whether or not any of them
are null or not null,
So it's going to show
us the non-null values,
so you can extrapolate there
how many null values
that you might have,
and then it's also going
to indicate the datatypes,
Keep in mind that a string is
an object in these palettes,
So by using head,
tail, size, and info,
I can get a little bit of
information about what's
going on inside of my DataFrame,
Let's now turn our attention to
the code that actually makes
all of this magic happen,