>> Let's see how we could explore
a DataFrame using a
little bit of code,
So let's first again import in
our pandas and let's
create that DataFrame,
Now you might be wondering, hey,
why in the world would you start
exploring a DataFrame when
you've hard-coded in what
that's going to look like?
Again, you're exactly right,
We're going to show
a little bit later
how we can load up some data,
We just want a simple
DataFrame that we
could start to show off
some of the skills,
So that way when it comes time
to load up some data that we
know better of what's
going on and how to start
exploring all of that,
So there we go,
I'm just going to
create my DataFrame,
There it all is, and
now let's explore it,
So like we mentioned before,
head will give us the ability to see
the top three rows
because I specify three,
If I specify two for example,
as you might expect that
it's going to give us back
just simply those two items,
Five, I think you'll start to
see where all of this as going,
it will just give you
back that number of rows,
If you want to start from the bottom,
then you could simply use tail,
and that will just count
up from the bottom,
So if we take a look,
you'll notice that there
is the bottom of that,
Certainly, it'll read
a Pearson and Changi,
and if we take a look over here,
we can see back in our
original DataFrame,
that's exactly what we've got there,
If I just want to see
what's the shape,
what does it look
like, seven and three,
Again, remember that the
three is giving us the
number of data columns,
so it's not counting the index,
Then finally, I can see
the full info of that,
So I can see the columns,
I can see the names,
I can see how many items in
there are not null, etc,
I would say of all the information
that's going to give you,
the none null is probably going to
be one of the most important
things because working with
null values can really be
a struggle because sometimes
they'll indicate that
there's just missing data,
Sometimes, it will
indicator condition,
when you start doing math with them,
things start to go
sideways very quickly,
Null values are really a struggle,
So being able to see
real quickly, hey,
what's my data look like is
going to be really powerful,
and it really is going to
be probably the first thing
you will always do when
you load up some data,
especially data that
you're not overly familiar
with to see what it is
that you're working with,
Now you've got the tools
to be able to do that,