>> Now that we've seen how we
could grab some rows
from our DataFrame,
get the overall structure of it,
let's get in and see
how we could start
to pull out different pieces of data,
Now you're going to
notice about a DataFrame,
the fact that there's a lot of
different methods and tools
and so forth that are at
your disposal for getting in and
finding basically anything
that you might want,
performing all sorts of different
manipulations and so forth,
We're going to take a
look at a couple of
these as we go through the
next handful of videos here,
But I want to stress
the fact that we're
not going to go through everything,
If you go check out
the documentation linked
to from our GitHub page,
you'll be able to see everything
that's available to you
and begin to just continue
to grow your tool set,
But let's get in and see how we
can identify individual items
or start slicing and dicing our data,
So how can we go grab specific rows
and specific columns or how can
we slice and or dice our data
where we're grabbing full column,
s full rows etc,
Well, one way that we can
do this is by grabbing
a specific column by identifying
it based on its name,
that you'll notice that the
indexer for DataFrame is
going to by default be
the name of the column,
So if I say airport city,
that's going to give us back
everything that's inside
of that city column
as well as the index,
So when I do that, boom,
I've got my city and I've got
the index to go along with that,
How about if I want
two different columns?
Well, if I want two
different columns,
then what I need to do is I
need to actually pass in,
where is my cursor?
Here, Let me put that to red,
there we go, now I can
find it, There we go,
So what I can do is I can
create a list like I've
got here with the name of
each column that I want,
So you'll notice that I'm identifying
my name and my country there,
So those are going to be the
two columns that I want back,
The main thing that I want you
to notice about the syntax
here is the fact that we're
putting this inside of a list,
If we didn't put that
inside of a list,
then what we're actually
doing is passing in
different parameters
into that indexer
and that's not the
way that it behaves,
We want to pass in one parameter,
That one parameter is
going to be a list,
So that little bit of
square bracket that you're
seeing inside of there,
that's got to be there,
So that way we can identify, hey,
these are the columns,
Cool, So that's how I can
get individual columns,
Now, let's say that I
want to go in and grab
things based on their position
that sometimes I'm
going to have the name,
sometimes I'm going to
have the column that
maybe what I'm trying to
do is loop through things,
Maybe I want to see
where something is specifically
inside of a DataFrame,
It may do happen to know
the location and so
that's what I want to be
able to go in and do,
This is especially helpful
if maybe I want to
specify a range of columns
or a range of rows,
So what I can do is I can use my
ilocation or my index location,
But there we go, with my ilocation,
might index location now
what I can do is specify
the rows and the columns
by index that I want,
So if I do 0, 0,
like I've got right here,
as you might expect,
that's going to give us
right here, Seattle-Tacoma,
So if I run this code,
if you will on my slide,
that's what we're going to get back,
If I say 2, 2,
that's going to count down again,
zero-based, so 0, 1, 2,
it's actually going
to give us the third
and the third that's
going to give us,
in this case, United Kingdom,
Now you might notice on the slide,
and this will be true on the
next couple of slides as well,
that little spot right up there,
that column 0, column 1,
column 2, those are not
actually part of the DataFrame,
They're just there to help make
our demo a little bit easier here,
So that why you can see where 0,
1, and 2 actually are,
So 0, 0, Seattle-Tacoma, 2,
2 is going to give us the
United Kingdom there,
You can also go in
and specify a range,
This is what I was mentioning before,
where things are actually
a little bit more powerful
when you're using
that index location is the ability
to specify a range of values,
So similar to using a range on, say,
a list where I could
go in and specify
one colon and then whatever
my end index is going
to wind up being,
maybe for example, for I can
do the exact same thing here,
So let's start off by
using colon and colon,
When I pass in those
ranges on either side,
or in this case both sides,
what I'm indicating
is that I want all of
the values from my
rows or my columns,
So if you remember from before,
the first parameter that's going
to indicate the rows that I want,
Second parameter that's going to
indicate the columns that I want,
When I say colon and colon,
I'm saying all rows and all columns,
So if I run this, I'm going
to get back that highlighted
section there where I'm
going to get everything,
If I said, "Hey,
I only want, in my case,
the first two rows,"
so it's going to be 0,
1 and then stopping at index 2,
but not including it,
then I could go in and
specify that as my range,
This is now going to indicate that we
want back all of our columns,
So if I run this, I'm now going to
get back Seattle-Tacoma,
Seattle, USA,
and Dulles, Washington,
USA as my values back,
So first two rows and all columns,
I could go the other
direction as well,
where maybe I put that
over on the columns side,
So now that's going to give me
back the first two columns,
So that's going to give me
back the name and the city
and we get our index as well,
How about if I want to specify
a list of items there?
So maybe what I want
to get back is I want
to get back the first column,
and in my case, the third column,
Remember again, counting
starts at zero,
so zero and two,
column 0 and column 2,
The way that I can do that
is by specifying a list,
I want to highlight
here the difference
between a range and a list,
My range allows me to specify the
starting point and the endpoint,
whereas my list here
is going to give me
the ability to specify the
individual items that I want here,
So in my case,
I don't want the first column
and I want the third column,
So zero and two, there we go,
I'm going to specify zero and two,
Those are the columns
that I want back,
You'll notice the colon at
the beginning that's going to
specify that we want all of the rows,
So if I run this,
now what I'm going to get
is my name and my country,
and again the index as well,
If you want to do this by name,
then you can just
simply use location,
So just LOC,
Now if I specify name and country,
that would give me
back the exact same,
but only doing it by name
instead of by the index,
Well, now that we've
seen a little bit of
slide representation,
what do you say?
We see this in action,
Let's open up a notebook and see
how we can actually use these tools,